黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, Chim chiminy Chim chim cheree
煙囪清掃工就是幸運星
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, Chim chiminy Chim chim cheroo
當他和你握手的時候，幸運就會傳染給你
Good luck will rub off when he shakes hands with you
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy Chim chim cheree, chim cheroo
Rum diddly-diddly-diddly
Rum diddle-die
女士們，先生們
All right, ladies and gents...
這樣的場合，幽默詩正好派上用場
comical poems suitable for the occasion...
即興創作，當場發表
extemporized and thought up before your very eyes.
好的，我們開始
All right, here we go.
這是我們共同的天地
Room here for everyone Gather around
警察先生剋盡職守
The constable's "responstable".
聽起來還不錯吧？
Now, how does that sound?
你好，拉克小姐 讓我為你獻上一首
Hello, Miss Lark I got one for you
拉克小姐喜歡和安德魯在公園散步
Miss Lark likes to walk in the park with Andrew.
你好啊，安德魯
Hello, Andrew.
啊，考利夫人 一個關於你的故事
Ah, Mrs Cory a story for you
你的女兒過去比你矮……
Your daughters were shorter than you...
但現在，她們長高了
but they grew.
親愛的帕西蒙小姐
Dear Miss Persimmon...
嗯？
Yes?
風，從東方刮來
Wind's in the east
霧，在四處瀰漫
Mist comin' in.
一件醞釀已久的事情看似就要發生
Like something is brewin' about to begin
沒人能夠預測未來
Can't put me finger on what lies in store
但我知道將要發生的一切……
But I feel what's to happen...
都曾經發生過
all happened before.
對不起，剛才說到哪裏了？
I'm sorry. Where was I?
謝謝，謝謝你的支持
Thank you, one and all, for your kind support.
啊，拉克小姐，謝謝。
Ah, Miss Lark, thank you.
天主保佑你
Crikey. Bless you, guv.
您就是慷慨的化身
Generosity itself, that's what you are.
您就免了。
No charge.
哦，是你啊！你好。
Oh, it's you! Hello.
你是說，櫻桃樹大街17號麼？
Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane, you say?
好吧，跟我來。
All right. Come along with me.
這就是櫻桃樹大街
This here's Cherry Tree Lane.
一個很可愛的地方
Nice little spot, you might say.
17號就在前面
Number 17's just down a bit.
這個能給人留下深刻印象的大房子第一眼看上去並不舒服
Now, this imposing edifice what first greets the eye...
它是退役海軍上將
is the home of Admiral Boom...
鮑默將軍的家
late of His Majesty's Navy.
他的房子就像一艘船
Likes his house shipshape, he does...
他做事更是井井有條，一絲不茍
shipshape and bristol fashion at all times.
報時槍準備 準備完畢，將軍
Time gun ready?
Ready and charged, sir.
還有3分零6秒 是，將軍
Three minutes and six seconds.
Aye, aye, sir.
將軍一向以準時而聞名
What he's famous for is punctuality.
全世界都以格林尼治時間為準
The whole world takes its time from Greenwich.
但人們說格林尼治以將軍的時間為準
But Greenwich, they say, takes its time from Admiral Boom.
情況還好麼，將軍？
What cheer, Admiral?
下午好，年輕人。你要到哪兒去？
Good afternoon to you, young man. Where are you bound?
17號那兒有個聚會，我想去看看
Number 17. Got some parties here in tow what wants to see it.
把這事記入航海日誌 是，將軍
Enter that in the log.
Aye, aye, sir.
應該提醒你，年輕人
A word of advice, young man:
17號地區的暴風雨跡像已經很明顯
Storm signals are up at Number 17.
天氣馬上就要變壞
Bit of heavy weather brewing there.
謝謝，我會留神的
Thank you, sir. Keep an eye skinned.
這就是櫻桃樹大街17號
Here we are. Number 17 Cherry Tree Lane.
喬治?班克斯先生的住所
Residence of George Banks, Esquire.
噢，將軍的話一點都沒錯
Hello, hello, hello. The Admiral's right.
17號地區的天氣很惡劣
Heavy weather brewin' at Number 17, and no mistake.
別理她！ 住嘴！
Leave her alone!
Shut up!
我告訴你，不要試圖阻止這個惡人！
I'll show you. Don't you be trying to stop the wretched creature!
讓她走，我說，她走了真好！
Let her go, that's what I say, and good riddance!
從她踏進門的那刻起，我就沒喜歡過她
I never liked her from the moment she set foot in the door.
但沒有了保姆，誰來對付那兩個孩子？我麼？天！
But who gets stuck with the children with no nanny in the house? Me, that's who!
瞧她那高傲的樣子！
Her and her high and mighty ways!
還有她那張臉，我已經受夠了
And that face of her that would stop a coal barge, it would.
事實上，布裏夫人！你就是把全世界的財寶
Indeed, Mrs Brill! I wouldn't stay in this house another minute...
都堆在我面前，我也不會再多呆一分鐘
not if you heap me with all the jewels in Christendom.
不，不，卡蒂保姆，別走！
No, no, Katie Nanna, don't go!
別擋著門
Stand away from that door, my girl!
你讓我們怎麼和主人說孩子的事呢？
But what am I gonna tell the master about the children?
這與我無關。這是那兩個小野獸最後一次從我這溜走。
It's no concern of mine. Those little beasts have run away from me for the last time.
他們一定在什麼地方。你去動物園找過了麼？
They must be somewhere. Did you look around the zoo in the park?
你瞭解簡和邁克爾
You know how Jane and Michael is.
你難道不擔心獅子會抓住他們嗎？
Coo! You don't think the lion could've got at them, do ya?
你知道他們是多喜歡在那籠子周圍玩
You know how fond they was of hangin' around the cage.
我不想再廢話了
I said my say, and that's all I'll say.
這所房子已經和我永遠一刀兩斷
I've done with this house forever.
好啊，好極了
Well, hip, hip, hooray!
出門當心別摔了，寶貝
And don't stumble on the way out, dearie.
噢，別這樣，卡蒂保姆！
Now, now, Katie Nanna!
班克斯夫人！她回來了！
Mrs Banks! She's home!
我們女兒的女兒會敬仰我們 我們將一起歡唱
Our daughter's daughters will adore us and we'll sing in grateful chorus
「幹得好，主張參政的姐妹們」
"Well done, Sister Suffragette"
卡蒂保姆，艾倫，晚上好
Good evening, Katie Nanna, Ellen.
我們舉行了一場盛大的聚會！
We had the most glorious meeting!
威伯尼夫人把自己綁在首相的馬車車輪上
Mrs Whitbourne-Allen chained herself to the wheel of the Prime Minister's carriage.
你們真應該去看看 班克斯夫人，我有句話要對你說
You should've been there.
Mrs Banks, I would like a word with you.
還有阿什列夫人被抓走了
And Mrs Ainslie, she was carried off to prison...
她一路上邊唱歌邊散發傳單
singing and scattering pamphlets all the way!
我很高興你回來了，夫人，我已經盡力了
I'm glad you're home, madam. I've always given the best that's in me...
謝謝你，卡蒂保姆
Oh, thank you, Katie Nanna.
我就知道我不會看錯的
I always knew you were one of us.
我們是身著裙裝的戰士
We're clearly soldiers in petticoats
為婦女的投票權而英勇地戰鬥
And dauntless crusaders for women's votes
儘管我們尊敬每一個男人
Though we adore men individually
但作為一個群體，他們是愚蠢的
We agree that as a group they're rather stupid
班克斯夫人 甩掉昨日的枷鎖
Mrs Banks.
Cast off the shackles of yesterday
肩並肩，我們走向自由
Shoulder to shoulder into the fray
我們女兒的女兒將會敬仰我們
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
她們將一齊歡唱
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
「幹得好 主張參政的姐妹們」
"Well done Sister Suffragette"
可能的話，我不想冒犯你，但是……
Being that as it may, I do not wish to offend, but I...
從肯辛頓到比林斯門呼聲此起彼伏
From Kensington to Billingsgate one hears the restless cries
從這片土地的每一個角落 婦女們站起來了
From every corner of the land womankind arise
政治平等 權利平等
Political equality and equal rights with men
潘克赫斯特夫人又被銬上
Take heart for Mrs Pankhurst has been clapped in irons again
我們不再做溫順的附屬品
No more the meek and mild subservients we
為了我們的權力英勇奮鬥
We're fighting for our rights militantly
Never you fear
班克斯夫人，我能插句話麼？
If I may have a word, Mrs Banks.
甩掉昨日的枷鎖 班克斯夫人！
So cast off the shackles of yesterday
Mrs Banks!
肩並肩我們走向自由
And shoulder to shoulder into the fray
我們女兒的女兒將會敬仰我們
Our daughter's daughters will adore us
她們將一齊歡唱
And they'll sing in grateful chorus
「幹得好」 班克斯夫人
"Well done"
Mrs Banks.
「幹得好」 班克斯夫人
"Well done"
Mrs Banks.
班克斯夫人！
"Well done, Sister Suf..."
Mrs Banks!
什麼事？ 班克斯夫人，我有件事要告訴你
What is it, Katie Nanna?
Mrs Banks, I have something to say to you.
孩子們在哪裏？ 夫人，孩子們……
Where are the children?
The children, madam...
確切地講，不在這裏
to be precise, are not here.
他們又消失了
They've disappeared again.
卡蒂保姆，你確實太粗心了
Katie Nanna, this is really too careless of you.
這已經是這周的第三次了
Doesn't it make the third time this week?
第四次，夫人。如果不是氣憤之極的話
The fourth, madam. And I for one have had my fill of it.
我並不想說他們的壞話
I'm not one to speak ill of the children, but...
你估計他們什麼時候能回來？
Oh, please, when do you expect them home?
這可不好說。現在請你算一算我的薪水
I really couldn't say. And now if you'd be good enough to compute my wages, I'll...
噢，天，卡蒂保姆！你不是要走吧？ 班克斯先生會怎麼說？
Oh, gracious, Katie Nanna! You're not leaving? What will Mr Banks say?
他回家後，發現孩子們不見了會很生氣的
He's going to be cross enough as it is to come home and find the children missing.
艾倫，把這些拿開，你知道這東西會讓他多惱火
Ellen, put these things away. You know how the cause infuriates Mr Banks.
是的，婦人
Yes, ma'am.
卡蒂保姆，我請求你，再想一想
Katie Nanna, I beseech you. Please reconsider.
想想孩子們，想想班克斯先生
Think of the children. Think of Mr Banks.
他剛開始適應你
He was just beginning to get used to you.
各就各位！
Posts, everyone!
4，3，2，1，點火！
Four, three, two, one. Fire!
卡蒂保姆，我請求你…… 我的薪水，請！
Katie Nanna, I do beseech you...
My wages, if you please.
今晚早了點，是嗎？將軍
Bit early tonight, aren't you, Admiral?
胡說，正點報時，跟往常一樣
Nonsense. Bang on the dot, as usual.
銀行裏的事情還好吧？
How are things in the world of finance?
從沒有比現在更好的時候了，貨幣堅挺，貸款利率不斷上升
Never better. Money's sound. Credit rates are moving up, up, up.
英鎊成了全世界的寵物
And the British pound is the admiration of the world.
很好 先生，你那兒的情況怎麼樣？
Good man.
How do things look from where you stand?
很難講
Bit chancy, I'd say.
起風了，氣壓也下降了
The wind's coming up and the glass is falling.
我不喜歡這種情況 好，好，好
Don't like the look of it.
Good, good, good.
班克斯，毫無疑問你將趕上壞天氣的
Banks, shouldn't wonder if you weren't steering into a nasty piece of weather.
班克斯！你聽見了麼？
Banks! Do you hear me?
你好，卡蒂保姆。那一定很重吧。
Hello, Katie Nanna. That must be heavy.
讓我來吧
Allow me.
哼！
Hmph!
多可愛的帽子啊！
What a very pretty hat.
就像一位國王
I feel a surge of deep satisfaction
騎著他的駿馬，謝謝
Much as a king astride his noble steed Thank you.
當我擺脫白天的喧囂，回到家，回到妻子身邊
When I return from daily strife to hearth and wife
我是多麼心滿意足，我的生活多麼愉快！
How pleasant is the life I lead
親愛的，有件事和孩子們有關 是的，是的，是的
Dear, it's about the children.
Yes, yes, yes.
我按照日程表精確地管理著我的家！
I run my home precisely on schedule
6點01分 我走進家門
At 6:01 I march through my door
6點02分 放下我的手套和手杖
My slippers, sherry and pipe are due at 6:02
我的生活始終如一！
Consistent is the life I lead
喬治，孩子們不見了。 太美妙了。
George, they're missing.
Splendid. Splendid.
1910年在愛德華國王的統治下
It's grand to be an Englishman in 1910
做一位英國男人是多麼光榮 這是一個男人唯上的時代
King Edward's on the throne It's the Age of Men
我是城堡的主人 統治者
I'm the lord of my castle The sovereign, the liege
我管理著我的僕人，孩子們和妻子
I treat my subjects, servants children, wife
嚴格且溫和，貴族的行為理應高尚
With a firm but gentle hand Noblesse oblige
現在6點03分，我領地的繼承人們
It's 6:03 and the heirs to my dominion
已經洗過了，吃飽了
Are scrubbed and tubbed and adequately fed
我會拍拍他們的頭，打發他們去睡覺
And so I'll pat them on the head
and send them off to bed
啊，我的生活多麼氣派！
Ah, lordly is the life I lead
威妮弗蕾德，孩子們在哪兒？ 他們不在這裏，親愛的
Winifred, where are the children?
They're not here, dear.
什麼？他們當然應該在這兒！他們會在別的地方嗎？
What? Well, of course they're here!
Where else would they be?
我不知道，喬治 你不知道？
I don't know, George.
You don't know?
他們不見了。卡蒂保姆到處都找遍了
Well, they're missing. Katie Nanna has looked everywhere.
我要立即處理這件事
Very well. I'll deal with this at once.
請給我接警察局，快！
Give me the police station, quickly, please.
我想這件事不必麻煩警察，事實上……
I don't think we need bother the police, dear. The facts of the matter...
請別試圖用什麼事實把事情弄得模糊不清
Kindly do not attempt to cloud the issue with facts.
唯一的事實，很明顯，卡蒂保姆不能勝任她的工作
One fact, and one fact alone is crystal clear! Katie Nanna's faltered at her post.
她使得這個家陷入混亂，我要教訓教訓她……
She's let the family down. And I shall bring her to bo...
哦，她已經走了，是嗎？
Oh. She's left us, hasn't she?
是的，親愛的，剛剛走
Yes, dear, only just.
喂，呃……我是喬治?班克斯
What, uh... Yes. George Banks here.
櫻桃樹大街17號。出了件急事
Yes. 17 Cherry Tree Lane. It's a matter of some urgency.
請立即派一名警察
I should like you to send a policeman around immediately.
喬治，警察來了！
The policeman's here, George!
什麼？噢，真及時！服務真好！
What? Oh, how very prompt. What wonderful service.
謝謝！晚安
Thank you so much. Good night.
請進，警察先生，請進！ 謝謝！
Come in, Constable. Come in.
Thank you, sir.
我在公園那邊巡邏時
While going about my duties on the other side of the park...
發現了兩件遺失的貴重物品
I noted some valuables that had gone astray.
我相信是你的，先生 貴重物品？
I believe they're yours, sir.
Valuables?
來，過來
Come along, now. Come along.
簡！邁克爾！
Jane! Michael!
威妮弗蕾德，請別激動
Winifred, please don't be emotional.
哦，他們今天走了很多路，精疲力盡了
Oh, I wouldn't be too hard on 'em, sir. They've had a long, weary walk today.
孩子們，過來
Children, come here at once.
怎麼回事？ 對不起，我們和保姆卡蒂走散了
Well?
I'm sorry we lost Katie Nanna, Father.
你知道的，今天風很大，而這個風箏對我們來說大了點
You see, it was windy. And the kite was too strong for us.
在某種意義上說，先生，是風箏跑走了而不是孩子們
In a manner of speaking, sir, it was the kite that ran away, not the children.
謝謝，警察先生。我想我能夠控制這件事
Thank you, Constable. I think I can manage this.
說實話，這風箏並不好。我們自己做的
Actually it wasn't a very good kite. We made it ourselves.
也許你可以幫我們做一個……
Perhaps if you helped us to make one...
哦，那很重要，先生。風箏很難控制
Ah, that's the ticket, sir. Kites are skittish things.
就在上周，我和我的孩子們……
Why, only last week with me own youngsters...
我非常感謝你送他們回來
I'm very grateful to you, Constable, for returning the children.
如果你到廚房看看，廚師會給你弄些吃的
And I'm sure that if you go to the kitchen, Cook'll find you a plate of something.
謝謝你，先生。我該回去工作了
Thank you, sir. I shall now return to my duties.
謝謝你，警察先生
Thank you, Constable.
晚安，小姐。晚安，夫人，晚安，先生
Good night, miss. Good night, ma'am.
Good night, sir.
廚師會給我弄些吃的。我從沒……
Cook'll find me something. I never...
喬治，我非常非常抱歉
I'm awfully sorry about this, George.
我猜你大概要談談這件事
I'll expect you'll want to discuss it.
的確！
I would indeed!
艾倫，帶簡和邁克爾到樓上去
Ellen, take Jane and Michael upstairs straightaway.
好的，先生
Yes, sir.
我就知道。誰首當其衝的負擔這一切？
I knew it. When all's said and done, who bears the brunt of everything around here?
我！就是這樣！
Me, that's who!
他們不想要一個誠實勤勞的人
They don't want an honest, hard-workin' girl around here.
他們需要的是動物園看守
They need a ruddy zookeeper.
我很抱歉，親愛的。我當初之所以選中了卡蒂保姆……
I'm sorry, dear, but when I chose Katie Nanna...
是因為她看上去那麼嚴厲
I thought she would be firm with the children.
她看上去會嚴格地要求孩子們。
She looked so solemn and cross.
威妮弗蕾德，不要把效率和急躁混為一談
Winifred, never confuse efficiency with a liver complaint.
下次我會試著幹得好一點
I'll try to do better next time.
下次？親愛的，過去的四個月裏你已經換了六個保姆
Next time? My dear, you've engaged six nannies in the last four months!
個個都是不稱職的災星 我同意
And they've all been unqualified disasters.
I quite agree.
給孩子們選保姆是一項重要而細緻的任務
Choosing a nanny for the children is an important and delicate task.
它要求深入的觀察，公正的判斷，還有識別人的能力
It requires insight, balanced judgment, and an ability to read character.
在這種情況下，只好由我親自來……
Under the circumstances, I think it might be apropos to take it upon myself to, uh...
呃，處理了
select the next person.
噢，喬治？！ 顯然想要選出一位合適的保姆
Oh, would you, George?
Obviously the way to find a proper nanny...
就應該採用恰當的方式
is to go about it in a proper fashion.
我要在《泰晤士報》上登一則廣告。請你記下來
I shall put an advertisement in the Times. Take this down please.
當然，是的，親愛的。 招聘
Yes, of course, dear.
Wanted.
呃，不，呃，要求一位……
Uh, no. Uh, required.
嚴厲、受人尊敬言談穩重的保姆
Nanny: Firm, respectable, no nonsense.
以為英國的保姆應該像一位將軍
A British nanny must be a general
帝國的未來就掌握在她的手中
The future empire lies within her hands
因此我們需要塑造孩童的人
And so the person that we need
to mould the breed
應該是一位能夠發號施令的保姆
Is a nanny who can give commands
你記下來了麼，威妮弗蕾德？ 噢，是的，親愛的，一字不差
You getting this, Winifred?
Oh, yes, dear. Every word.
一家英國銀行的運作在準確無誤的基礎上
A British bank is run with precision
一個英國家庭也要求絲毫不差
A British home requires nothing less
傳統，紀律和規則是我們的工具
Tradition, discipline and rules
must be the tools
失去了這些，將陷入混亂，災難，無政府狀態
Without them, disorder catastrophe, anarchy
總之，可怕的混亂
In short you have a ghastly mess
精闢，喬治！很有啟迪
Splendid, George! Inspirational.
《泰晤士報》會很滿意的
The Times will be so pleased.
父親？ 什麼？
Father?
Yes?
我們已經商量過了
We've discussed everything...
對今天的所做作為，我們感到非常抱歉
and we're very sorry about what we did today.
我想應該是的
I should certainly think so.
從卡蒂保姆那裏跑走是不應該的 是這樣
It was wrong to run away from Katie Nanna.
It was indeed.
我們這麼幹的目的就是想要換一位新的保姆
And we do so want to get on with the new nanny.
很明智。我很高興在這件事上能得到你們的幫助
Very sensible. I shall be glad to have your help in the matter.
我們認為你會同意的。所以我們寫了一份廣告
We thought you would. That's why we wrote this advertisement.
什麼廣告 招聘新保姆的
Advertisement for what?
For the new nanny.
你們寫了一份廣告…… 喬治，我想我們應該聽一聽
You wrote an advert...
George, I think we should listen.
你說過你需要我們的幫助 但我是……哦，好吧
You said you wanted our help.
But, I... Oh, very well.
為兩位極其可愛的孩子招聘一個保姆
"Wanted: A nanny for two adorable children."
及其可愛的？應該說是「極其難管」的
"Adorable." Well, that's debatable, I must say.
如果你想得到這個職位
If you want this choice position
你應該開朗活潑
Have a cheery disposition
簡，我不是…… 面龐紅潤，沒有疣子
Jane, I don't...
Rosy cheeks, no warts
那是我加進去的 精通各種遊戲
That's the part I put in.
Play games, all sorts
你必須善良和藹，聰明機智
You must be kind You must be witty
恬美可愛，且美麗漂亮
Very sweet and fairly pretty
好了，簡直荒唐透頂…… 喬治，別這樣！
Well, of all the ridic...
George, please!
帶我們出遊 款待我們
Take us on outings Give us treats
為我們唱歌 還要帶上甜點
Sing songs Bring sweets
從不發火
Never be cross or cruel
絕不拿蓖麻油和薄粥糊弄我們
Never give us castor oil or gruel
愛我們如同自己的子女
Love us as a son and daughter
還有不能有大麥茶味兒
And never smell of barley water
這條也是我加進去的
I put that in too.
如果你不斥責我們，壓制我們
If you won't scold and dominate us
我們絕不會做讓你恨我們的事情
We will never you give you cause to hate us
我們不會藏起你的眼鏡，讓你找不到
We won't hide your spectacles so you can't see
把青蛙放在你的床上，或把胡椒粉倒進你的茶裏
Put toads in your bed or pepper in your tea
好保姆，快點來
Hurry, Nanny
此致……敬禮
Many thanks Sincerely
簡和邁克爾?班克斯敬上
Jane and Michael Banks
謝謝。非常有趣
Thank you. Most interesting.
現在我聽夠了你們的胡言亂語
And now I think we've had quite enough of this nonsense.
回房間去吧
Please return to the nursery.
他們畢竟是個小孩子，他們只是想幫幫忙
They were only trying to help. They're just children.
我知道他們還是小孩子
I'm well aware they're just children, Winifred.
我很慶幸我決定介入這件事情
I only congratulate myself that I decided to step in and take a hand.
「遊戲，唱歌，甜點」
"Play games, sing songs, give treats."
荒唐！毫無疑問
Ridiculous. There's no question in my mind whatsoever.
該開始行動了
Now is the time for action.
請告訴我《泰晤士報》的號碼 不，我當然不知道號碼
Give me the Times, please. No, I do not know the number.
哦，喬治，你總是這麼強勢
Oh, George, you're always so forceful.
泰晤士報？我是喬治?班克斯
The Times? George Banks here.
櫻桃樹大街17號。我要在你們的欄目上登一則廣告
17 Cherry Tree Lane. I wish to place an advertisement in your column.
報時槍準備好了麼？ 準備完畢，將軍！
Time gun ready?
Ready and charged, sir.
請報告，賓納克先生
I'll take the report, Mr Binnacle.
是。風向已經轉變，好像來自一個新的區域
The wind has changed, sir. Seems
to be comin' in from a new quarter.
是的 先生？ 什麼事？
So it is.
Sir?
What is it?
左舷船首好像出事了
Bit of somethin' or other taking place off the port bow.
我不得不說，一群可怕的人
Ghastly looking crew, I must say!
門外的保姆排起了長隊，先生。能讓她們進來了麼？
Coo! There's a fair queue of nannies outside, sir. Shall I show 'em in?
艾倫，我說過了8點鐘開始，就8點
Ellen, I said 8:00, and 8:00 it shall jolly well be.
還有12秒
You see? Twelve seconds to go.
10，9，8…… 各就各位！
Ten, nine, eight... Posts!
7，6，5，4……
Seven, six, five, four...
3，2，1！
three, two, one!
艾倫，現在8點整了
Ellen, it is now 8:00.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
艾倫，我已經告訴你多遍……
But I have told you time and time again, Ellen...
我不喜歡做事沒有條理
I dislike being hurried into things.
我不明白，他們一點也不符合咱們的廣告
I don't understand. They're not what we advertised for at all.
邁克爾，看！
Michael, look!
不會是一個巫婆吧。
Perhaps it's a witch.
當然不是，巫婆都是騎著掃把
Of course not. Witches have brooms.
就是她，咱們想要的人。她看了我們的廣告
It's her. It's the person. She's answered our advertisement.
她符合咱們的每一個條件
Rosy cheeks and everything.
艾倫，你可以把她們帶進來了，一次一個
Ellen, you may now show them in, one at a time.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
你請進，每次一位 謝謝
You may come in one at a time.
Thank you.
哦
Oh.
你就是簡和邁克爾的父親嗎？
You are the father of Jane and Michael Banks, are you not?
我說，你是簡和邁克爾的父親嗎？
I said, you are the father of Jane and Michael Banks.
噢，是的，當然
Well, well ye... Yes, of course, I mean. Uh...
你帶了推薦信吧？我可以看看嗎？
You brought your references, I presume. May I see them?
哦，我的原則是不提供推薦信
Oh, I make it a point never to give references.
依我看，那已經過時了
A very old-fashioned idea to my mind.
是麼？我們還是有必要看一看
Is that so? We'll have to see about that then, won't we?
現在，看看廣告上的要求吧
Now then, the qualifications.
第一條：開朗活潑
"Item one: A cheery disposition."
我從不生氣
I am never cross.
第二條：面龐紅潤
"Item two: Rosy cheeks."
顯而易見
Obviously.
第三條：會做各種遊戲
"Item three: Play games, all sorts."
我可以肯定孩子們會發現我的遊戲花樣繁多
Well, I'm sure the children will find my games extremely diverting.
這張紙，你從哪裏弄到的？我記得我已經把它撕了
May I? Eh, this paper? Where did you get it from? I thought I tore it up.
抱歉，第四條：必須善良和藹
Excuse me. "Item four: You must be kind."
我很善良，但非常嚴格
I am kind, but extremely firm.
你丟了什麼東西嗎？ 啊！是
Have you lost something?
Ah! Yeah.
那張紙，我想我……
That paper, you see. I thought that I...
你是喬治?班克斯先生嗎？ 什麼？
You are George Banks, are you not?
What?
你登了廣告招聘保姆，是嗎？
And you did advertise for a nanny, did you not?
喬治?班克斯 那就好
George Banks.
Very well then.
我撕了它，轉過來
I tore it up, turned it over.
又撕了一下，然後扔在哪兒
Tore it up again and threw it in there. Yes.
請原諒，你生病了嗎？
I beg your pardon. Are you ill?
我希望沒有
I hope not.
現在談談我的薪水吧。關於這一點這上面很模糊
Now, about my wages. The reference here is very obscure.
是很模糊 我們有必要明確下來
Very obscure.
We must be very clear on that point, mustn't we?
的確有必要 每隔一個星期二我得休息一天
Yes, we must indeed.
I shall require every second Tuesday off.
每個星期二
Every Tuesday.
另外，規定一個試用期也許是明智的做法
On second thoughts, I believe
a trial period would be wise.
我給你一個星期的時間
Hmm. I'll give you one week.
I'll know by then.
我去看看孩子們，謝謝你
I'll see the children now. Thank you.
邁克爾，把你的嘴閉上，我們不是鱈魚
Close your mouth please, Michael. We are not a codfish.
別光站在那兒看，走吧
Well, don't stand there staring. Best foot forward.
動作快點
Spit spot!
喬治？ 哈？
George?
Aah!
喬治，你到底在做什麼？
George, what on earth are you doing?
我還以為你正在面試那些保姆呢 剛才還是！
I thought you were interviewing nannies.
I was! I was!
你是說你已經選完了？
You mean you've selected one already?
是的，都結束了。 那麼，她在哪兒？
Yes, it's done. It's, it's all done.
Well, where is she?
什麼？她在孩子們的房間裏
What? Well, eh, she's in
the nursery of course, I mean.
我的意思是讓她開始工作了。 你太英明了
I put her to work straightaway, I mean.
How clever of you!
要是我一定會把事情搞砸的
I would have muddled the whole thing.
告訴我，她是不是符合我們的所有要求？
Tell me, is she everything that we'd hoped she be?
一切都發生得太快了，我的意思是……
Well, i-it all happened rather quickly. I mean, I... I, uh...
她嚴厲嗎？她會發號施令嗎？
Will she be firm? Will she give commands?
她能塑造孩子們嗎？
Will she mould our young breed?
我想她能
You know, Winifred, I think she will.
那麼，也許最好讓艾倫
I think she will. In that case...
告訴其他的人可以走了
perhaps you'd better tell Ellen to dismiss the others.
其他人？哦，是的，艾倫？ 是的，先生？
The others? Oh, yes. Ellen?
Y-Yes, sir?
告訴其他人可以走了，這位置已經有了合適的人選
Tell the other applicants they may go. The position has been filled.
其他人？ 是的，其他人。
The others, sir?
Yes, the others.
她以為我們需要幾個保姆
How many nannies does she think we need in this house?
這個位置已經有了合適的人選
The position has been filled.
恐怕我們的房間不夠整潔
I'm afraid the nursery isn't very tidy.
就像一個大熊的窩，對嗎？
It is rather like a bear pit, isn't it?
你的包真滑稽 是地毯
That's a funny sort of bag.
Carpet.
你是說包裏裝的是地毯嗎？ 不，是用地毯做的
You mean to carry carpets in?
No. Made of.
這是你的房間，從這裏可以欣賞到公園
This is your room, and there's a lovely view of the park.
嗯
Hmm.
好吧，畢竟不是白金漢宮
Well, it's not exactly Buckingham Palace.
還挺乾淨
Still, it's clean.
我覺得它很合適
Yes, I think it will be quite suitable.
只是到處需要整理一下
Just needs a touch here and there.
首先，就像我常說的那樣
Well, first things first.
掛帽子最合適的地方就是衣帽架
I always say, the place to hang a hat is on a hat stand.
哈！這怎麼能用呢？
Ah! This will never do!
我更喜歡大一點的
I much prefer seeing all of my face at the same time.
但是裏面是空的呀！
There... But there was nothing in it.
不要根據表面現象作判斷
Never judge things by their appearance.
即使是一隻地毯包。我就從來沒有
Even carpetbags. I'm sure I never do.
美麗的東西永遠是快樂的
A thing of beauty is a joy forever.
嗯，也許應該更亮一些
Mmm, a little more light, perhaps.
我們最好多留心這傢伙
We better keep an eye on this one.
她很狡猾。 她棒極了。
She's tricky.
She's wonderful.
這下好多了！
Much better!
我瞧瞧
Now, let me see.
奇怪，我總是隨身帶著的。一定放在什麼地方了
That's funny. I always carry it with me. It must be here somewhere.
什麼東西？ 類型測量尺
What?
My tape measure.
你找它來幹什麼？ 我想知道你們倆個屬於哪一類。
What do you want it for?
I want to see how you two measure up.
這是我見過的最好笑的事情。我知道它就在裏面的某個地方
Well, that's the funniest thing I ever saw. I know it's down here somewhere.
啊，哈哈，找到了
Ah, ha-ha, ha-ha! Here it is.
好，過來，快一點！
Good. Come along, then. Quickly.
抬起頭來，邁克爾。別無精打采的。
Head up, Michael. Don't slouch.
跟我想的一樣「非常倔強，多疑」
Just as I thought. Extremely stubborn and suspicious.
我沒有！ 自己看
I am not!
See for yourself.
極其頑固，且多……
"Extremely stubborn and sus..."
多疑！
Suspicious.
輪到你了，簡
Now you, Jane.
嗯，「愛傻笑，不把東西放好」
Mmm. "Rather inclined to giggle. Doesn't put things away."
那麼你呢？
How 'bout you?
我們來看看吧，拿著！
Very well. Hold this for me.
正如我所預料的，「瑪麗?潑平斯」
As I expected. "Mary Poppins."
「一切都近乎完美」
"Practically perfect in every way."
瑪麗?潑平斯！這是你的名字嗎？真可愛
Mary Poppins! Is that your name? It's lovely.
謝謝。我也一直很喜歡它
Thank you. I've always liked it.
現在，我們可以開始了吧？ 開始什麼？
Now, shall we get on with it?
Get on with what?
在廣告裏，你不是特別提到了會做各種遊戲嗎？
In your advertisement, did you not specifically request to play games?
哦，是的！ 很好，那麼……
Oh, yes!
Very well, then.
我們的第一個遊戲就叫做「好的開始是成功的一半」
Our first game is called "Well Begun Is Half Done".
我不喜歡，聽上去不太好
I don't like the sound of that.
換個名字就叫「讓我們開始整理房間」
Otherwise entitled, "Let's Tidy Up the Nursery".
我告訴過你她很狡猾
I told you she was tricky.
我們可以開始了麼？ 瑪麗?潑平斯，你認為這是個遊戲麼？
Shall we begin?
It is a game, isn't it, Mary Poppins?
這取決於你如何看待它
Well, it depends on your point of view.
你要知道，在每一件我們必須要完成的工作裏
You see, in every job that must be done...
都蘊含著快樂的成分
there is an element of fun.
你要發現快樂，抓住它！
You find the fun, and snap!
工作就變成了遊戲
The job's a game.
你承擔的每一項任務都變得輕鬆
And every task you undertake becomes a piece of cake
愉快，充滿了樂趣
A lark, a spree
顯而易見
It's very clear to see
一湯匙糖可以
That a spoonful of sugar
幫助你把藥喝下去
Helps the medicine go down
甜藥好入口
The medicine go down Medicine go down
只要一湯匙糖就能幫助你把藥喝下去
Just a spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go down
讓人意猶未盡
In a most delightful way
正在築巢的知更鳥，沒有空閒去休息
A robin feathering his nest has very little time to rest
它要一點一點地收集築巢的材料
While gathering his bits of twine and twig
儘管它那樣執著於工作，但它仍然唱著快樂的歌
Though quite intent in his pursuit he has a merry tune to toot
因為他知道，歌聲會使工作變得輕鬆愉快
He knows a song will move the job along
因為一湯匙糖能幫助你把藥喝下去
For a spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go down
甜藥好入口
The medicine go down Medicine go down
只要一湯匙糖能幫助你把藥喝下去
Just a spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go down
讓人意猶未盡
In a most delightful way
蜜蜂採集花蜜
The honeybees that fetch the nectar from the flowers to the comb
嗡嗡嗡，飛來飛去，從不厭倦
Never tire of ever buzzing to and fro
因為它們從采過的每一朵花裏只汲取了一點點
Because they take a little nip from every flower that they sip
因此…… 因此……
And hence
它們發現…… 它們發現……
They find
它們的任務不再沉重
Their task is not a grind
真無恥
Cheeky.
別沒完沒了得了
Don't be all day about it, please.
放我出去！
Let me out!
好了！非常……
Well, that was very...
非常感謝……
Thank you now...
現在，你應該結束了！
When you've quite finished!
謝謝！
Thank you.
到此為止吧。請拿上你們的外套和帽子
That will be quite sufficient. Hats and coats, please.
接下來，我們去公園
It's time for our outing in the park.
我不想出去，我還想整理房間
I don't want an outing. I want to tidy up the nursery again.
適可而止是最好不過的了，請跟上來
Enough is as good as a feast. Come along, please.
讓我瞧瞧，你這樣子還不夠好
Let me look at you. Well, you're not as well turned out as I'd like.
幸好，還有時間
Still, there's time. There's time.
動作快點！出發
Spit spot! And off we go.
因為一湯匙糖能幫助你把藥喝下去
For a spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go down
甜藥好入口
The medicine go down Medicine go down
只要一湯匙糖能幫助你把藥喝下去
Just a spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go down
讓人意猶未盡
In the most delightful way
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, Chim chiminy Chim chim cheroo
我做我喜歡的事情，我喜歡……
I does what I likes And I likes
我做的事情
What I do
你好，熱愛藝術的人！
Hello, art lovers.
正如你所看到的，今天我是個馬路畫家
Today I'm a screever and as you can see
馬路畫家是最高水平的藝術家
A screever's an artist Of highest degree
這是我記憶中所有的作品
And it's all me own work from me own memory
雖然不是出於英國皇家藝術院
Well, not Royal Academy, I suppose.
但是看上去還是非常不錯的吧？
Still they're better than a finger in your eye, ain't they?
黑煙囪……冒黑煙
Chim chiminy, Chim chiminy Chim chim cheroo
我畫我喜歡的，我喜歡我畫的
I draws what I likes and I likes what I drew
我不索取任何報酬
No remuneration do I ask of you
但我的帽子很歡迎
But me cap would be glad of a copper or two
一兩個銅板
Me cap would be glad of a copper or two
等等！別動
Wait! Don't move.
千萬別動
Don't move a muscle.
就呆在那兒！
Stay right where you are.
我就知道！瑪麗?潑平斯！
I'd know that silhouette anywhere! Mary Poppins!
很高興再見到你，伯特。這是簡和邁克爾
It's nice to see you again, Bert. I expect you know Jane and Michael.
我上次看見他們，正在追一隻風箏，對吧？
Well, I've seen 'em here and about. Chasin' a kite last time, weren't it?
瑪麗?潑平斯要帶我們去公園
Mary Poppins is taking us to the park.
去公園？我知道瑪麗?潑平斯是不會的
To the park? Not if I know Mary Poppins.
別的保姆會帶孩子們去公園，但是……
Other nannies take children to the park.
你們現在是和瑪麗?潑平斯在一起，一下子你們就到了連做夢都想不到的地方
When you're with Mary Poppins, suddenly you're in places you've never dreamed of.
迅速到你都還沒察覺
And quick as you can say "Bob's your uncle"...
最不尋常的事情就開始了
the most unusual things begin to happen.
你再說什麼，我一點也不知道
I'm sure I haven't the faintest idea what you're talking about.
好吧，你知道我本來不應該說的，但是……
Well mind, it's not my place to say, but what she's probably got in mind...
她腦子裏有一個令人興奮的好地方
is a jolly holiday somewheres or other.
沿著這些線就能到哪兒，對此我是不應感到驚訝的
Something along these lines, I shouldn't be surprised.
「在泰晤士河上泛舟」如果你們喜歡出遊，那絕對是個好去處
"Punting on the Thames." That's always good if you like an outing.
我們到了
Here we go.
馬戲團。去看看可愛的馬戲團如何？有獅子和老虎
The circus. How about a lovely circus? Lions and tigers.
舉世聞名的雜技演員為你……
World-famous artistes performing death-defyin' feats...
表演精彩絕倫的節目
of dexterity and skill before your very eyes.
Ta-da!
哦，那太可愛了。如果你願意的話，我更想去那兒！
Oh, that's lovely. If you please, I'd much rather go there.
很美，是嗎？典型的英國鄉村景象……
Beautiful, ain't it? A typical English countryside...
好像出自一位真正的鄉村愛好者之手
as done by a true and lovin' hand.
沿著這條路走下去，翻過這座山……
Though you can't see it, there's a little country fair...
有一個鄉村集市，不過你現在看不見
down that road and uh, over the hill.
這兒根本就沒有路
I don't see any road.
什麼？沒有路？
What? No road?
只要在這兒添點東西就行了……
Just wants a bit of somethin' here...
還有那兒
and a bit of somethin' there.
好了，一條鄉村小路很適合旅行和探險
There. A country road suitable for travel and high adventure.
請讓我們去吧，瑪麗?潑平斯
Please may we go, Mary Poppins? Please?
多可愛的地方啊！你不覺得它很可愛嗎？
Such a lovely place. Don't you think it's lovely, Mary Poppins?
現在正是時候，瑪麗?潑平斯。沒人注意
Now's the time, Mary Poppins. No one's lookin'.
求求你了，瑪麗?潑平斯！
Please, Mary Poppins. Please!
我可不願意出自己的醜，謝謝了
I have no intention of making a spectacle of myself, thank you.
好吧，我自己來
All right, I'll do it myself.
你要幹什麼？ 變個小魔法
Do what?
Bit of magic.
魔法？ 是的，很容易
A bit of magic?
It's easy.
讓我來看看。你頭腦裏想著
Let's see. You think.
眨一下眼睛
You wink.
眨兩下
You do a double blink.
閉上眼，跳！
You close your eyes and jump.
什麼都沒發生啊
Is something 'sposed to happen?
伯特，別胡鬧了！
Bert, what utter nonsense!
你為什麼總是把很簡單的事情弄複雜了
Why do you always complicate things
that are really quite simple?
把手給我，邁克爾。抬起頭
Give my your hand, please, Michael. Don't slouch.
1，2
One, two.
瑪麗?潑平斯，你看上去真漂亮
Mary Poppins, you look beautiful.
你真的這樣認為嗎？ 憑良心說，確實是。就像我初次見到你的時候一樣
Do you really think so?
Cross my heart you do. Like the day I met ya.
你也很棒，伯特
You look fine too, Bert.
我記得你說過那兒有一個集市
I thought you said there was a fair.
是的，沿著這條路往前，山後就是，記住了嗎？
So I did. Down the road behind the hill, remember?
快來！我聽到了旋轉木馬的聲音
Come on! I hear the merry-go-round.
告訴他們是伯特讓你們去的 別摔了，弄髒了畫！
Tell 'em Bert sent ya.
Don't fall and smudge the drawing.
多麼美妙的一天
Ain't it a glorious day
就在這五月的早晨
Right as a mornin' in May
我想要飛翔
I feel like I could fly
別鬧了，伯特
Now, Bert. None of your larking about.
你見過這麼嫩綠的草地嗎
Have you ever seen the grass so green
或比這更湛藍的天空嗎？
Or a bluer sky
噢，跟瑪麗在一起就是一個快樂的假日
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
瑪麗讓你的心變得輕鬆 你一點都沒有變，是吧？
Mary makes your heart so light
You haven't changed a bit, have you?
灰暗陰沉的日子裏
When the day is grey and ordinary
瑪麗讓它陽光明媚 噢，的確
Mary makes the sun shine bright
Oh, honestly!
幸福在她的周圍蕩漾
Oh, happiness is bloomin' all around her
洋水僊正對著小鴿子微笑
The daffodils are smilin' at the dove
當瑪麗牽著你的手，你感到無比的驕傲
When Mary holds your hand you feel so grand
你的心跳動比得上一個軍樂隊
Your heart starts beatin' like a big brass band
你有點頭暈腦漲了 和瑪麗在一起是一個快樂的節日
You are lightheaded.
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
毫無疑問，瑪麗是我們的鍾愛
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
和瑪麗在一起就是一個快樂的節日
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with Mary
瑪麗讓你的心輕鬆
Mary makes your heart so light
灰暗陰沉的日子裏
When the day is grey and ordinary
瑪麗讓它陽光明媚
Mary makes the sun shine bright
幸福在她的周圍蕩漾
Oh, happiness is bloomin' all around her
洋水僊正對著小鴿子微笑
The daffodils are smiling at the dove
Oink, oink.
當瑪麗牽著你的手，你感到無比的驕傲
When Mary holds your hand you feel so grand
你的心跳動比得上一個軍樂隊
Your heart starts beatin' like a big brass band
和瑪麗在一起是一個快樂的節日
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
毫無疑問，瑪麗是我們的鍾愛
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
謝謝 非常榮幸，瑪麗?潑平斯
Thank you.
Our pleasure, Mary Poppins.
伯特，和你在一起就是一個快樂的節日
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
像你這樣的紳士少而又少 正在消失
Gentlemen like you are few
A vanishing breed, that's me.
你是裹在破舊衣裳裏的鑽石
Though you're just a diamond in the rough, Bert
你的血統是高貴的 這誰都知道
Underneath your blood is blue
Common knowledge.
你從不炫耀
You'd never think of pressing your advantage
克制是你的原則 是的
Forbearance is the hallmark of your creed
True.
有你的陪伴，女士不再恐懼
A lady needn't fear when you are near
你的溫柔甜蜜 彬彬有禮
Your sweet gentility is crystal clear
伯特，和你在一起就是一個快樂的節日
Oh, it's a jolly holiday with you, Bert
一個快樂幸福的節日
A jolly, jolly holiday with you
服務生！
Waiter!
來點什麼呢？
Now then, what'd be nice?
先來一份冰鎮山莓
We'll start with raspberry ice
再來些糕點和茶
And then some cakes and tea
您不再點些別的嗎？ 我們這兒不收費
Order what you will
There'll be no bill
免費贈送
It's complimentary
你們真是太好了
You're very kind.
願意為你效勞，瑪麗?潑平斯
Anything for you, Mary Poppins.
你是受歡迎的人
You're our favourite person.
你說對了，梅維斯和希爾比常有辦法取勝
Right you are. It's true that...
Mavis and Sybil have ways that are winnin'
普魯登斯和格溫多林能讓你激動不已
And Prudence and Gwendolyn set your hearts spinnin'
菲比總是高高興興，莫德很善解人意
Phoebe's delightful Maude is disarming
珍妮絲，費利西婭和莉迪亞很可愛
Janice
Felicia
Lydia
Charming
辛西婭很迷人，維維安很甜美，斯蒂芬妮很了不起，普裏西拉很好客
Cynthia's dashing, Vivian's sweet Stephanie's smashing, Priscilla a treat
韋洛尼加，米莉森特，艾格尼絲和簡
Veronica
Millicent
Agnes
And Jane
是一些樂觀的好夥伴，再來一遍
Convivial company time and again
道克斯，菲利斯和格林尼斯是運動員
Dorcas and Phyllis and Glynis are sorts
我同意他們是三個最出色的運動員
I'll agree they're three jolly good sports
但，最優秀最出類拔萃的是……
But cream of the crop Tip of the top
是瑪麗?潑平斯 就到這裏
Is Mary Poppins
and there we stop
當瑪麗牽著你的手，你感到無比的驕傲
When Mary holds your hand you feel so grand
你的心跳動比得上一個軍樂隊
Your heart starts beatin' like a big brass band
和瑪麗在一起是一個快樂的節日
It's a jolly holiday with Mary
毫無疑問瑪麗是我們的鍾愛
No wonder that it's Mary that we love
Ya-hoo!
Ya-hoo! Ya-hoo!
我們私人的旋轉木馬
Ya-hoo! Our own private merry-go-round.
很好，事實上……
Very nice. Very nice, indeed...
如果你們不想去其他的地方
if you don't wanna go nowhere.
誰說我們不打算去其他地方？
Who says we're not going anywhere?
管理員！
Oh, guard!
好的，瑪麗?潑平斯
Righto, Mary Poppins.
謝謝
Thank you.
他們走了！瑪麗?潑平斯領先兩馬身
They're off! It's Mary Poppins leadin' by two lengths.
簡領先一馬身，邁克爾第三
Jane is second by a length. Michael third.
我的馬跑得最快
My horse is the fastest.
夥計，你聽到了麼？你甘心落後嗎？
Do you hear that, mate? Do you wanna put up with that?
來吧，咱們比賽一下。女士。這是你最快的速度嗎？
That's the ticket! Come on, my lad. Is that the best you can do?
加油，加油！
Hurry up, boy. Hurry up!
別跑那麼快，邁克爾！
Not so fast, please. Michael!
伯特，你真淘氣，像個孩子
Now really, Bert. You're as bad as the children.
對不起，慢點，慢點
Sorry. Whoa, boy! Whoa!
慢點
Whoa.
Easy, boy. Whoa. Whoa.
這可真是趟奇特的旅行
Just a bit of high spirits, Mary Poppins.
請你控制一下自己。咱們不是在賽馬場上
Please control yourself. We are not on a racecourse.
請跟我來
Follow me, please.
早上好 好……呃？怎麼回事……
Good morning. Oh, yes, quite. Wha...
我說！
I say!
你有沒有
Have you ever?
從沒有！
Never!
發現狐貍！
View Halloo!
哦，是的，絕對，發現狐貍了
Oh, yes, definitely. A view Halloo.
發現狐貍？
View Halloo?
天！又是那些英國兵！
Faith and begorra! 'Tis them Redcoats again!
發現狐貍！
View Halloo!
Oh, musha, musha.
可憐的傢伙，讓我來幫你一把吧
Poor lit'I bloke. Let's give him a hand.
聖人啊，保佑我們！
Saints preserve us!
呀！
Yikes!
跑啊！
Tally ho! Da-doo, da-doo!
你上來吧，抓好了！
Up you go. Now hang on.
你看清楚了麼？這可是了不起的旋轉木馬
Would you look at that now? 'Tis an elegant merry-go-round horse.
過來比試比試呀，你們這幫壞蛋
Come on and fight, you dirty omadhauns.
我能揍扁你們
I can lick the lot of ya's.
快點，美人，快點！
Faster, me beauty! Faster!
噢！騎手們，我可以先行一步嗎？
Oh, riders, would you be so kind as to let me pass?
當然可以，夫人
Certainly, ma'am.
謝謝 不客氣，夫人
Thank you.
Not at all, ma'am.
非常好的成績，先生們
Excellent time, gentlemen.
哦，是的，非常好 完美的成績，當然
Oh, yes, quite.
Perfect day for it, of course.
多漂亮啊
Oh. Oh, how nice.
萬歲！萬歲！
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
現在別動，看鏡頭
Hold still, now. Watch for the dickie bird.
瑪麗?潑平斯，請你談談取得勝利後的感受
Uh, how does it feel, Mary Poppins, winning the race?
好的，我…… 贏得了巨大的財富和榮譽吧？
Oh, well I...
Gaining fame and fortune.
是的 可以將你的照片刊登在報紙上嗎？
Uh, Yes.
Having your picture taken for the newspaper.
當然，我很願意
Uh, oh, actually, I'm delighted.
除了你精彩的照片外，你能說幾句話描述一下你的心情嗎？
Besides having your extreme good looks, if I may say so.
好的，我…… 有沒有一個詞能形容你此刻的心情
Oh, well, I wouldn't go...
There probably aren't words to describe your emotions.
先生們，先生們，很抱歉
Now, now, now, now, gentlemen, please.
不過有一個非常好的詞
On the contrary, there's a very good word.
對吧，伯特？ 告訴他們是什麼吧
Am I right, Bert?
Tell 'em what it is.
好的
Right!
那就是「超級霹靂快樂的不得了」
It's supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
儘管聽起來很糟糕
Even though the sound of it is something quite atrocious
但是如果你大聲地說出來，聽起來就好像你很博學
If you say it loud enough you'll always sound precocious
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle, Um diddle ay
當我還是一個小男孩的時候，我很害怕說話
Because I was afraid to speak when I was just a lad
我父親擰著我的鼻子說我太差勁了
Me father gave me nose a tweak and told me I was bad
但有一天我學會了一個詞，它救了我的鼻子
But then one day I learned a word that saved me achin' nose
你聽過的最長的一個詞
The biggest word you ever heard and this is how it goes
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Oh, supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
儘管聽起來很糟糕
Even though the sound of it is something quite atrocious
但是如果你大聲地說出來，聽起來就好像你很博學
If you say it loud enough you'll always sound precocious
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle, Um diddle ay
他周遊世界
He's travelled all around the world and everywhere he went
每到一處他就用這個詞，人們都說她很聰明
He'd use his word and all would say "There goes a clever gent"
我和羅馬的公爵，印度的邦主一起消遣
When dukes and maharajahs pass the time of day with me
我說這個奇怪的詞，他們便請我喝茶
I'd say me special word and then they'd ask me out to tea
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Ooh, supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
儘管聽起來很糟糕
Even though the sound of it
is something quite atrocious
但是如果你大聲地說出來，聽起來就好像你很博學
If you say it loud enough you'll always sound precocious
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
Um diddle diddle diddle, Um diddle ay
你知道，你也可以倒過來說……
You know, you can say it backwards, which is...
了得不的樂快靂霹級超
dociousaliexpistic-fragilcalirupus.
但你不認為這樣太長了點嗎？ 毫無疑問
But that's going a bit too far, don't you think?
Indubitably.
所以當你實在無話可說的時候，沒有必要沮喪
So when the cat has got your tongue there's no need for dismay
就想想這個詞吧，然後你會有很多話要說
Here, here! Just summon up this word and then you've got a lot to say
不過，要小心用好它，因為它會改變你的生活
But better use it carefully or it could change your life
比如說？ 怎樣？
For example.
Yes?
一天晚上，我對一個女孩說起它，這個女孩就成了我的妻子
One night I said it to me girl, and now me girl's me wife.
她還是那麼可愛
Ow! And a lovely thing she is too.
那就是，超級霹靂快樂的不得了
She's supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
超級霹靂快樂的不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
簡！邁克爾！
Jane! Michael!
靠近些
Stay close now.
哦，伯特，可惜你那些美麗的畫
Oh, Bert, all your fine drawings.
沒關係，它的出處還有好多
Well, there's more where they came from.
再說，我就要改行了，這鬼天氣，真能熱死人
Meantime, I'm changing businesses. This here is lovely hot chestnut weather.
來吧，孩子們 再見，伯特
Come along, children.
Bye, Bert.
再見
Bye-bye.
Bye, Bert. Bye.
再見，簡和邁克爾
Bye, Jane and Michael.
Bye, Bert.
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy Chim chim cheroo
La dum da da dum
da da da da dum
不，不，我不想吃你這討厭的藥。
No, no, I won't take your nasty medicine!
必須得吃麼，瑪麗?潑平斯？
Do we have to, Mary Poppins?
弄濕腳的人就必須得吃藥
People who get their feet wet must learn to take their medicine.
我不想吃，我真不想……
I don't want it. I'm not gonna...
Oh!
酸橙汁！味道好極了！
Lime cordial! Delicious!
草莓汁！
Strawberry! Mmm!
朗姆酒
R-R-Rum punch.
真可口
Quite satisfactory.
瑪麗?潑平斯，你永遠都不會離開我們的，是嗎？
Mary Poppins, you won't ever leave us, will you?
你的枕頭底下有沒有手帕？ 嗯
Do you have a handkerchief under your pillow?
Mm-hmm.
如果我們發誓做一個乖孩子，你會留下來嗎？
Will you stay if we promise to be good?
阿呃！那是一個脆弱的諾言。輕易地許下，輕易地違背
Och! That's a piecrust promise. Easily made, easily broken.
沒有了你，我們該怎麼辦？
Whatever would we do without you?
我將呆到風向改變了為止
I shall stay until the wind changes.
但是，瑪麗?潑平斯，那會多長時間呢？
But, Mary Poppins, how long will that be?
請安靜些，你們該睡覺了
Silence, please. It's time to go to sleep.
哦，我們根本睡不著。今天遇到了那麼多有趣的事情
Oh, we couldn't possibly go to sleep! So many lovely things have happened today.
有嗎？ 是啊！當我們跳進伯特的粉筆畫裏
Did they?
Yes! When we jumped into Bert's chalk picture.
我們騎著旋轉木馬，突然所有的木馬都一躍而起
And we rode the merry-go-round, and all the horses jumped off, and...
我們飛馳在原野上
And we all went riding in the countryside!
真的嗎？
Tally Ho! Tchunga! Tchunga! Yikes!
Really?
瑪麗?潑平斯，你都不記得了嗎？你還得了賽馬冠軍
Mary Poppins, don't you remember? You won the horse race!
一個像我這樣受尊重的人出現在賽馬會上？你們怎麼敢暗示這樣的事
A respectable person like me in a horse race? How dare you suggest such a thing.
但是我看見了，是你！
But I saw you do it!
別說了，否則，我就要叫警察了！明白嗎？
Now, not another word or I shall have to summon the policeman. Is that clear?
確實是這樣的！我看見了！
It did happen! I saw it!
去睡覺吧 不，我不想睡
Go to sleep.
No, I don't want to go to sleep.
瑪麗?潑平斯，我們太興奮了！
Mary Poppins, we're much too excited!
好吧，隨你們的便
Very well, suit yourselves.
保持清醒
Stay awake
別放鬆你的腦子
Don't rest your head
別躺在
Don't lie down
你的床上
Upon your bed
當月亮漫步在……
While the moon drifts
夜空的時候
In the skies
別睡著了
Stay awake
不要合上你的眼睛
Don't close your eyes
雖然整個世界都已入睡
Though the world Is fast asleep
雖然你的枕頭柔軟舒適
Though your pillow's soft and deep
你並沒有昏昏欲睡
You're not sleepy as you seem
別睡著
Stay awake
別打盹
Don't nod
別做夢
And dream
別睡著
Stay awake
別打盹
Don't nod
別做夢
And dream
今天天氣很好，賓納克先生。
Glorious day, Mr Binnacle. Glorious!
今早不會再有人睡懶覺了，裝雙倍的火藥
No one sleeps this morning. Put in a double charge of powder.
雙倍的火藥？是，將軍！
A double charge? Aye, aye, sir.
會震得更厲害，是嗎？
Shake things up a bit, what?
多可愛的早晨啊，艾倫 的確是，夫人
Lovely, lovely morning, Ellen.
Indeed it is, ma'am.
你把那些臭雞蛋放到我的包裏了嗎？ 放了，夫人
Have you put the spoiled eggs in my carryall?
Yes, ma'am.
在艾伯特禮堂的集會結束後，我們將去唐寧街……
After our meeting at the Albert Hall, we're all going to Downing Street...
把這些東西扔在首相的身上
to throw things at the Prime Minister.
你今天早上看上去非常好，喬治
Oh, how distinguished you look this morning, George.
廚房裏那可怕的噪聲是怎麼回事？
What's all that fearful caterwauling in the kitchen?
那是廚師在唱歌 唱歌？她怎麼了？
It's Cook singing.
Cook singing? What's wrong with her?
她快樂得像一隻蟋蟀，老實講……
She's happy as a cricket. As a matter of fact...
從你僱用瑪麗?潑平斯那天起，這屋子裏似乎發生了……
since you hired Mary Poppins, the most extraordinary thing...
不同尋常的變化 有這回事？
seems to have come over the household.
Is that so?
就拿艾倫來說吧，她今早沒有打碎一隻盤子
Take Ellen for instance. She hasn't broken a dish all morning.
真的？那太不同尋常了 還有……
Really? Well, that is extraordinary.
And another thing.
他和廚師總是像貓見了狗一樣打個不停，但是今天
She and Cook usually fight like cats and dogs, but today...
艾倫，親愛的，我來給你開門吧 謝謝
Let me hold the door for you, Ellen dear.
Thanks ever so, ducks.
艾倫，快停止你那恐怖的歌聲吧！
Ellen, stop making that offensive noise!
把窗戶關上，那鳥叫得我頭痛
And shut the window! That bird's giving me a headache.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
安靜點，你們鬧得主人頭痛
Quiet! You're giving the master an headache.
我很擔心你今天早上感覺不好
I'm so sorry you're not feeling well this morning, George.
誰說我的感覺不好？我非常健康
Who said I'm not feeling well? I'm fit as a fiddle.
我只是搞不懂為什麼每個人都這麼興奮
I just don't understand why everyone's so confoundedly cheerful!
超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
這花真可愛，謝謝，寶貝！
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious How lovely. Thank you, my darling.
超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
停！停！停！ 早上好，父親
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Good morning, Father.
早上好 瑪麗?潑平斯教給我們最有趣的一個詞
Good morning. Mary Poppins taught us the most wonderful words.
超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
你們到底在說些什麼？超級……
What on earth are you talking about? Supercali...
究竟是什麼意思？
Super... Or whatever the infernal thing is.
當你不知道該說什麼的時候，你就可以這樣說
It's something to say when you don't know what to say.
但是我總是知道我該說些什麼，走開，請你們快點離開這裏
Yes, well, I always know what to say. Go on, hurry along, please.
好的，父親 超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Yes, Father. Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious
威妮弗蕾德，你能解釋一下這不體面的喧鬧究竟是為什麼嗎？
Winifred, will you be good enough to explain this unseemly hullabaloo?
我沒覺得有什麼需要解釋的
I don't think there's anything to explain. Do you?
很明顯你今天早晨有點不舒服
It's obvious that you're out of sorts this morning.
孩子們近來只是想讓你感覺好一些
The children just came in to make you feel better.
我最後一次聲明
I should like to make one thing quite clear, once and for all.
我並沒有感到不舒服，我的狀態很好
I am not out of sorts. I am in a perfectly equable mood.
我不需要別人的安慰
I do not require being made to feel better!
但是你常說希望我們的家充滿了歡樂和愉快
But you're always saying that you wanted a cheerful and pleasant household.
威妮弗蕾德，在愉快和輕率不負責任之間……
Winifred, I should like to make a slight differentiation...
我要做一點區分
between the word cheerful and just plain giddy irresponsibility.
打斷一下，親愛的，大家各就各位！
Excuse me, dear. Posts, everyone, please!
我並不反對任何人的歡樂和愉快
I have no objection to anyone being cheerful or pleasant.
但我堅持合乎傳統的禮儀
But I do expect a certain decorum.
我要告訴你的是，我不會袖手旁觀
I can tell you one thing, Winifred. I don't propose standing idly by...
看著那個女人，瑪麗?潑平斯摧毀這個家庭的規矩
and letting that woman, Mary Poppins, undermine the discipline and...
自從她來了以後
There's something odd, I may say extremely odd...
這房子裏出了很多非常奇怪的事情
about the behaviour of this household since that woman arrived.
我想讓你知道，我已經注意到了 是的，親愛的
And I want you to know that I've noticed it!
Yes, dear.
還有件事情 什麼，親愛的？
One thing more.
Yes, dear?
找個人把鋼琴修理一下
I suggest you have this piano repaired.
當我坐在一件樂器前面的時候，我希望它別走調
When I sit down to an instrument, I like to have it in tune.
可是，喬治，你平常不彈呀！
But, George, you don't play.
夫人，這並不重要！
Madam, that is entirely beside the point!
讓我來看看，首先，我們得去找一位調音師
Now, let me see. First of all, we must go to the piano tuners.
然後去考利夫人的……
And then we go to Mrs Cory's sh...
商店，買些姜味麵包 哈，姜味麵包！
Mrs Cory's shop for some gingerbread.
Ah, gingerbread!
然後還要到魚販那兒買一尾新鮮的鰨科魚
And then we go to the fishmonger's, I think, for a nice dover sole...
以及一品脫對蝦
and a pint of prawns.
呃，邁克爾，別在後頭慢慢吞吞的
Uh, Michael, stop stravaging along behind.
哈嗨！
Ahoy, there! Ahoy!
很高興見到你們 早上好，將軍
Good day to you!
Good morning, Admiral.
邁克爾，今天我們去哪兒探險？
Michael, what fine adventure are we off upon today?
是去和霍屯督人戰鬥，還是去尋找寶藏？
Going to fight the Hottentots? Dig for buried treasure?
我們打算去買點魚
We're going to buy some fish.
非常好！全速前進
Very good! Proceed at flank speed.
遵命，長官
Aye, aye, sir.
小伙子，讓我們繼續
Let's put our backs into it, lad.
注意外表整潔，這是這兒的規矩
More spit and polish. That's what's wanted around here.
是安德魯
It's Andrew!
唔，不要太快，我一個字都沒聽清你說的
Uh, not so fast, please. I can't understand a word you're saying.
又發作了？可憐的人！
Again? Och! Oh, the poor man!
天主保佑你
Bless you.
當然，不能耽擱，我們立刻就去
Well, yes, of course. There's not a moment to lose. I'll go straightaway.
非常感謝你
And thank you very much.
他說了什麼？ 他說，不客氣
What did he say?
He said, "You're welcome".
他還說了什麼？ 我認為他什麼都沒有說
What else did he say?
I don't think he said anything.
你總是什麼都知道
You know best, as usual.
我以為我們要去買點魚 計劃有些變動
I thought we were gonna buy some fish.
There's been a change of plans.
跟上，別走丟了
Come along, please. Don't straggle.
安德魯，擔心起不了任何作用
Andrew, worrying won't help anyone.
你為何不回家休息休息一會兒呢？
Why don't you go home and put your feet up?
哦，伯特，很高興你也在這裏 我已聽說就立即趕過來了
Oh, Bert, I'm glad you're here.
I came over the moment I heard.
他怎麼樣了？
Well, how is he?
說實話，我從來沒見他這麼糟糕過
I've never seen him as bad as this, and that's the truth.
- Oh!
他們怎麼跟來了？你知道，這病有傳染性
How about them? It's contagious, you know.
我們會長水痘嗎？ 絕對不會的
Shall we get spots?
Oh, highly unlikely.
哦，艾伯特叔叔 天主保佑，保佑我的靈魂
Oh, Uncle Albert!
Oh, bless me. Bless my soul.
是瑪麗?潑平斯，我很高興
It's Mary Poppins! I'm delight...
我很高興見到你，瑪麗 艾伯特叔叔，你發過誓的
I'm delighted to see you, Mary.
- Uncle Albert, you promised!
我知道……
Oh, I kn... I know, I...
我努力了，真的……
But I tried. Really, I did, my dear. I...
但是我太喜歡笑了，你知道嗎？
But I so enjoy laughing, you know? And, well...
我一旦笑起來，就無法控制
And when I start, it's all up with the...
就像現在這樣
That's what happens to me.
我喜歡笑！我的天！
I love to laugh! Oh, my goodness!
你看到了，我情不自禁
I can't help it. You can see that.
我就是喜歡笑，沒別的
I just like laughing, that's all.
簡，你敢！你會讓他病情惡化的！
Jane, don't you dare! You'll only make him worse.
情況確實挺嚴重的 是的，無論如何，你都必須保持嚴肅
It's really quite serious!
Yes, whatever you do, keep a straight face.
上次，我們花了三天時間才把他弄下來
Last time, it took us three days to get him down.
我愛歡笑
I love to laugh
爽朗的清晰的長久的笑
Loud and long and clear
我愛歡笑
I love to laugh
一年比一年嚴重
It's getting worse every year
我越是笑
The more I laugh
就越是感到高興
The more I fill with glee
你在這裏起不到任何幫助 越是高興
You're no help at all.
The more the glee
我就越是一個愉快的人
The more I'm a merrier me
這很令人為難
It's embarrassing.
我就越是一個愉快的人
The more I'm a merrier me
有些人從鼻子裏笑出來
Some people laugh through their noses
聽上去就像這樣
Sounding something like this
真煩人！
Dreadful!
有些人從牙縫裏笑出聲來
Some people laugh through their teeth, goodness sakes
嘶嘶嘶，就像一條蛇
Hissing and fizzing like snakes
依我看，一點意思都沒有
Not at all attractive to my way of thinking.
有些人笑得很快
Some laugh too fast
有些笑得很短暫
Some only blast
其他人，就像鳥兒一樣咯咯地笑
Others, they twitter like birds
你知道麼，你和他一樣嚴重
You know, you're as bad as he is.
有一種人從不掩飾他們的情緒
Then there's that kind what can't make up their mind
當有趣的事情向我襲來
When things strike me as funny
我無法將它隱藏
I can't hide it inside and squeak
不得不哈哈大笑
As the squeakelers do
只要一開始笑，就得開懷大笑
I've got to let go with a ho ho ho ho
然後
And laugh
哈哈大笑
Too
太好了！
How nice!
我一直期待你也來
I was hoping you'd turn up.
我們在一起過得很愉快
Turn up! We always have such a jolly time.
我們愛笑
We love to laugh
爽朗的清晰的長久的笑
Loud and long and clear
我們愛笑
We love to laugh
這樣每個人都能聽到
So everybody can hear
你越是笑
The more you laugh
哎喲，你們兩個別笑，回來
Whoops, don't you two start. Come back down here.
你越是充滿快樂
The more you fill with glee
你越是快樂
The more the glee
我們就越是愉快的人
The more we're a merrier we
歡迎你們，小朋友，請隨意
Oh, welcome, children! Welcome! Make yourselves comfortable.
沒錯，把椅子拉上來
That's right. Pull up a chair.
是的，拉上來……
Oh, pull up...
我不得不說你們是在出洋相
I must say, you're a sight, the lot of you!
說到出洋相，我倒是想起我的哥哥
Speaking of sight, it reminds me of me brother.
他在鐘錶廠有一份輕鬆的工作
He's got a nice cushy job in a watch factory.
在鐘錶廠？他做什麼？
In a watch factory? What does he do?
他一整天閒著做鬼臉（作鍾表面）
He stands about all day and makes faces!
他在一家鐘錶廠做鬼臉……
He makes faces in a watch fact...
你編的吧？
You made that up. I know.
太好了
That's so good!
瞧瞧你們的樣子
Such behaviour!
這是我見過的最不光彩的一幕，我情願我不再叫瑪麗?潑平斯
Well, it's the most disgraceful sight I've ever seen, or my name isn't Mary Poppins.
說到名字，我知道一個有一隻木頭假腿的人，名字叫史密斯 （也可理解為：我知道有個人，他有一隻叫做史密斯的木頭假腿）
Speaking of names, I know a man with a wooden leg named Smith.
那他的另一條腿叫什麼？
What's the name of his other leg?
很有意思吧？那他的另一條腿叫什……
Wasn't that funny? What's the name of his other...
孩子們，下午茶時間到了
Now, then, children, it's time for tea.
我可不願意我的日程被打亂
I will not have my schedule interrupted.
哦，請留步，看，我已經為你們準備了上好的茶
Oh, please stay. Look, I have a splendid tea all ready for you.
這茶已經涼了
And it's getting cold!
我本以為你會……
Well, I had hoped that maybe, that you would just, that...
好極了！非常感謝！
Splendid! Thank you very much!
請把腳收回去。啊，當心麵包和黃油
Keep your feet back. Mind the bread and butter. Now, watch it, children.
我知道她會這樣做的。 這也是合乎傳統的茶。
I knew she could bring it off.
And a proper tea it is too.
我猜，你想要我做的下一件事情就是為你倒茶
Next thing, I suppose, you'll be wanting me to pour out.
好吧，如果有必要，我一定去做
Oh, well. If I must, I must.
如果你們不要像一群笑個不停的獵狗
If you'll just stop behaving like a pack of laughing hyenas!
兩塊糖嗎？艾伯特叔叔？ 是的，謝謝
Two lumps, Uncle Albert?
Yes, please.
伯特，你呢？ 噢，不，不，不要糖
Uh, Bert?
Uh, no, no, thank you. No sugar for me.
我很高興你上來。如果你不來的話，就不好玩了
I'm so glad you came. It wouldn't be any fun without you.
給你自己還有邁克爾加點牛奶
Here, and you may pour some milk for Michael and yourself.
你不覺得今年的這個時候天氣非常的好嗎？
Nice weather we're having this time of year, don't you think?
哦，是的。呃，談到天氣……
Oh, yeah. Uh, speaking of weather...
有一天，天很冷
the other day when it was so cold...
我的一個朋友想去買件長一點的內衣
a friend of mine went to buy some long underwear, you know.
售貨員問，你打算要多長的（也可理解為：你打算要穿多久的）
The shopkeeper said to him, "How long do you want it?"
我的朋友回答說，大概從9月到3月
And my friend said, "Well, from about September to March."
簡！別太放肆了！
Jane! Control yourself!
孩子們，麻煩你們坐到桌子旁邊來
Children, will you please sit up properly at the table?
你的茶，艾伯特叔叔 噢，謝謝，親愛的
Your tea, Uncle Albert.
Oh, thank you, my dear.
我很開心，多麼希望你們能一直留在這裏啊
I'm having such a good time. I wish that you could all stay up here all the time.
我們很高興不得不留下，因為沒有路下去
We'll jolly well have to. There's no way to get down.
哦不，路是有的
Oh, no, there is a way.
坦誠地講，我不願提起它……
Frankly I, I don't like to mention it...
因為你得不得不想一些悲傷的事情
because you have to think of something sad.
那麼請開始吧
Then do get on with it, please!
讓我想想看
Let me see.
我知道一件非常合適的事情
I've got the very thing.
昨天隔壁的女士應聲去開門，一個人站在門外
Yesterday when the lady next door answered the bell, there was a man there.
他對女士說，我非常抱歉，我剛剛軋了你的貓
And the man said to the lady, "I'm terribly sorry. I just ran over your cat."
哦，真悲慘 可憐的貓咪
Oh, that's sad.
The poor cat.
接著，那個人說，我很願意替代那隻貓
And then the man said, "I'd like to replace your cat."
女士說，可以，但有一點，你捉老鼠的技術好不好？
And the lady said, "That's all right with me, but how are you at catching mice?"
我真的很努力讓自己傷心點，但是……
Well, you know I started out sad. I, I try, really I do.
一切都那麼好笑，我不能……
But, but everything ends up so hilarious, I can't...
我禁不住……
I can't help...
這已經夠了
That will be quite enough of that!
我們該回家了
It's time to go home.
唉，那太讓人難過了 哦，不！
Oh, that is sad.
Oh, no!
那是我聽過的最難過的事情了
Oh, that's sad. That's the saddest thing I ever heard.
來吧，孩子們
Come along, children. Spit spot!
你們必須得走嗎？
Must you really go?
你知道，大家來看望我
You know, people come to see me all the time, you know.
我們一起過得很愉快，然而他們不得不回家
And, and we have such a lovely time, and then they have to go home.
對此我會感到非常非常的傷心
And, and I'm very, very sad about the whole thing.
別難過，我們會很快再來的
Don't worry. We'll come back soon.
我們過得非常開心
We had a lovely time.
伯特，照顧好艾伯特叔叔，好嗎？
Uh, keep an eye on Uncle Albert, will you, Bert?
我會再陪他呆一會兒的 謝謝，來吧
I'll sit with him a while.
Thank you. Come on.
艾伯特叔叔，我有一個笑話專門留給這樣的場合的
Uncle Albert, I got a jolly joke I saved for just such an occasion.
你想聽聽看嗎？ 好啊，我非常感激
Would you like to hear it?
I'd be so grateful.
不必客氣，這是關於我爺爺的
Righto. Well, it's about me granddad, see?
有一天晚上，我爺爺做了一個惡夢
And one night, he had a nightmare, he did.
他害怕極了，以至於把枕頭咬成了碎片
So scared that he chewed his pillow to bits.
Yes.
成了碎片……第二天早晨，我說……
To bits.
Yes.
Next morning I says...
你感覺還好嗎？爺爺？
"How do you feel, Granddad?"
Yes.
他回答，呃，不壞，只是有點口乾
He says, "Oh, not bad. A little down in the mouth!"
我常說，沒有什麼東西比得上一個好笑話
Yeah, I always say there's nothing like a good joke.
確實是，啥也比不上好笑話
No. And that was nothing like a good joke! That...
班克斯，你今晚晚了些，是嗎？
Bit late tonight, aren't you, Banks?
我說，班克斯！出了什麼問題了，班克斯？
I say, Banks! Is anything the matter, Banks?
班克斯！
Banks!
噢，父親，真高興你回來了 想聽個笑話嗎？
Oh, Father, we're so glad you're home!
Want to hear a joke?
我們今天下午和瑪麗?潑平斯在一起過得非常愉快
We had the most wonderful afternoon with Mary Poppins.
說到下午的事情，那個笑話是這樣的
Speaking of afternoons, the joke goes like this.
我知道有個人名字叫史密斯，他有條假腿
I know a man with a wooden leg named Smith.
史密斯？我們不認識叫史密斯的人
Smith? We don't know anyone called Smith.
笑話還沒有講完，另一個傢伙問，他的另一條腿叫什麼名字
And there was a second chap, and the second chap says,
"What's the name of his other leg?"
我們還在天花板上開了一個非常棒的茶會
And we had a lovely tea party on the ceiling!
哦，孩子們，請安靜
Oh, children, please be quiet.
瑪麗?潑平斯說，如果我們乖，她還會帶我們去那兒的
Mary Poppins says if we're good, she'll take us there again.
哦，瑪麗?潑平斯這樣說的嗎？
Oh. Oh, Mary Poppins said that, did she?
請回到你們自己的房間去，好嗎？
Will you please return to your room.
瑪麗?潑平斯，請隨我來好嗎？
Mary Poppins, will you be kind enough to come with me?
好的
As you wish.
瑪麗?潑平斯，我很遺憾，有些話我不得不說
Mary Poppins, I very much regret what I must say to you.
晚上好，喬治，有什麼問題嗎？ 我恐怕是的
Good evening, George. Is anything the matter?
I'm afraid there is.
我很想留下來，但是我不得不換衣服了，因為今晚還有個集會
I, I'd love to stay, but I have to dress for my rally in Hampstead.
威妮弗蕾德，我希望你能留下來
Winifred, it is my wish that you be present!
好的，喬治，當然
Oh, yes, George, of course.
瑪麗?潑平斯，我不得不說，我對你感到非常失望
Mary Poppins, I must confess I am extremely disappointed in you.
終於輪到她了，我以前就聽過主人這樣講話
She's for it now. I've heard the master do this speech before.
我不否認對於孩子們將全部的時間……
I don't deny that I am partially responsible for allowing the children...
都浪費在毫無意義的遊戲上，我應該承擔一定的責任
to spend their days on worthless frivolity to the exclusion of all else!
但是，現在已經到了讓他們認識到生活的嚴肅性的時候
But it is high time they learned the seriousness of life!
但是，喬治，他們還是孩子
But, George, they're only children.
精確地講，鑒於已經發生的……
Precisely. And in the light of what has happened...
喬治，你肯定你在說些什麼嗎？
George, are you certain you know what you're doing?
我相信我知道，威妮弗蕾德
I believe I do, Winifred.
一家英國銀行運作於準確無誤的基礎之上
A British bank is run with precision
一個英國家庭也要運作與絲毫不差的基礎上
A British home requires nothing less
傳統，紀律和規則是我們必須的工具
Tradition, discipline and rules must be the tools
沒有了它們，混亂，無序……
Without them disorder, chaos
道德崩潰
Moral disintegration
總之，帶來的是可怕的，混亂不堪的局面 我非常贊同
In short you have a ghastly mess
I quite agree.
孩子們必須被引導，塑造和教導
The children must be moulded shaped and taught
生活是一場終究要面對和參與的戰鬥
That life's a looming battle to be faced and fought
總之，我很驚訝地聽到我的孩子們討論……
In short, I am disturbed to hear my children talking about...
跑到馬路上的粉筆畫裏……
popping in and out of chalk pavement pictures...
與馴馬師聯歡，獵狐
consorting with racehorse persons, fox hunting.
當然，這件事本身我並不反對
Yes, well I don't mind that quite so much.
畢竟，它是傳統的活動
At any rate, it's traditional.
但是，在天花板上的茶會，請問是怎麼回事？
But tea parties on the ceiling? I ask you.
在天花板上開茶會，以及其它各種令人疑惑的出遊！
Having tea parties on the ceiling and highly-questionable
outings of every other kind!
如果他們必須出遊的話，那麼，出遊應該有
If they must go on outings These outings ought to be
明確的目標和……是的，實際意義
Fraught with purpose Yes, and practicality
還有那些愚蠢的話
These silly words like
比如超……超級……
Superca... Super...
超級霹…… 超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Superca...
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious.
是的，很好，就是你說的
Yes, well done. You said it.
到畫裏面
And popping through pictures
毫無疑義，沒有任何必要
Have little use fulfil no basic need
他們需要開始認識真正的現實
They've got to learn the honest truth
儘管年紀還小，他們必須學會……
Despite their youth They must learn
向您那樣的生活 正是如此
About the life you lead
Exactly.
他們需要體會統計分類帳差額簿的興奮
They must feel the thrill of totting up a balanced book
成千個數字整齊地排成一行 很對
A thousand ciphers neatly in a row
Quite right.
當瞥一眼顯示利潤上升的圖標
When gazing at a graph that shows the profits up
興奮就溢滿他們那小小的心靈 的確如此
Their little cup of joy should overflow
Precisely!
他們應該學著沿著你的腳印走路 是的
It's time they learned to walk in your footsteps
My footsteps.
滿懷驕傲地沿著你的筆直且狹窄的道路前進 帶著驕傲
To tread your straight and narrow path with pride
With pride.
明天，正如你所建議的那樣
Tomorrow just as you suggest
Pressed and dressed
簡和邁克爾將會穿著整齊地和你一起
Jane and Michael will be at your side
好極了，你說的準確無誤……
Splendid! You hit the nail right on the...
和我一起？去哪兒？
At my side? Where are we going?
當然是去銀行，完全按照您的建議
To the bank, of course, exactly as you proposed.
我的建議？ 當然
I proposed?
Of course.
現在，如果你不介意，明天對於孩子們來講是個重要的日子
Now, if you'll excuse me. Tomorrow's an important day for the children.
我要讓他們睡個好覺，晚安
I shall see they have a proper night's sleep. Good night.
威妮弗蕾德，我說過要帶孩子們去銀行嗎？
Winifred, did I say that I was going to take the children to the bank?
聽上去確實是的，親愛的 哦
It certainly sounded that way, dear.
Oh.
為什麼不呢？一個極好的主意！
And why not? A capital idea!
這正是對付眼下混亂局面的一劑良藥
Just the medicine they need for all this slipshod, sugary...
他們在這裏接觸的都是女人的不切實際的想法
female thinking they get around here all day long.
好主意，非常好
Quite right. Good idea. Quite right.
Good idea. Quite right.
瑪麗?潑平斯，我們不讓你走
Mary Poppins, we won't let you go!
走？你們到底在說什麼？
Go? What on earth are you talking about?
你不是被解雇了嗎？ 解雇？當然沒有！我從來沒有被解雇過！
Didn't you get sacked?
Sacked? Certainly not!I am never sacked!
哦，瑪麗?潑平斯！ 好噢，好噢
Oh, Mary Poppins!
Hurrah, hurray, hurray,
我也不是五朔節花柱，請別圍著我轉。
hurray, hurray, hurray...
Neither am I a maypole. Kindly stop spinning about me.
但 但什麼但……
But?
Goats butt, birds fly...
孩子們，你們必須早點睡覺，明天要跟你們的父親一起出去
and children who are going on an outing with their father must get some sleep.
別這樣，求求你 跟父親出去？
Come along, please.
An outing with Father?
是的 我不信
Yes.
I don't believe it.
他以前從來沒有帶我們出去過 他從來沒有帶我們去任何地方
He's never taken us on an outing before.
He's never taken us anywhere.
你怎麼做到的？ 做到什麼？
However did you manage it?
Manage what?
你一定用了什麼方式把這主意塞到他的腦瓜裏了
You must've put the idea in his head somehow.
胡說！
What an impertinent thing to say!
我怎麼可能把主意塞進人們的腦袋裏？真是的！
Me putting ideas into people's heads? Really!
他要帶我們去哪裏？ 去銀行
Where's he taking us?
To the bank.
哇~邁克爾，去城裏！我們能看到好多風景，爸爸會指給我們看
Oh, Michael, the city! And we'll see all the sights, and Father can point them out to us.
是的，多數風景他能發現
Well, most things he can.
但有時候，我們所愛的人卻不能看到……
But sometimes a person we love through no fault of his own...
他眼皮底下的事情 眼皮底下的？
can't see past the end of his nose.
Past the end of his nose?
是的，有時候一些小事情其實非常重要
Yes. Sometimes a little thing can be quite important.
哦，看啊！這是主教座堂
Oh, look! The cathedral.
爸爸每天都從旁邊經過，他常看到
Father passes that every day. He sees that.
每天清晨，在聖保羅大教堂的台階上
Early each day to the steps of St Paul's
有一位孤獨的老婦人
The little old bird woman comes
用她自己獨特的方式
In her own special way
向人們叫賣著
To the people she calls
來買吧
Come buy my bags
鳥食
Full of crumbs
喂餵這些小鳥
Come feed the little birds
照顧它們
Show them you care
你會感到快樂
And you'll be glad if you do
它們的幼鳥非常飢餓
Their young ones are hungry
它們的鳥巢非常簡陋
Their nests are so bare
只要花您兩便士
All it takes is tuppence from you
來餵這些小鳥
Feed the birds
一袋兩便士
Tuppence a bag
只要兩便士
Tuppence, tuppence
兩便士一袋
Tuppence a bag
來餵這些小鳥
Feed the birds
她正是這樣叫賣
That's what she cries
在頭頂上
While overhead
鳥兒在空中盤旋
Her birds fill the skies
主教座堂頂上的所有聖人和使徒雕像
All around the cathedral the saints and apostles
都注視著她
Look down as she sells her wares
雖然你看不見
Although you can't see it
但每次有人顯示出
You know they are smiling
他的愛心，購買鳥食的時候
Each time someone shows
你知道雕像們正在微笑
That he cares
雖然老婦人的叫賣聲
Though her words
微弱而簡單
Are simple and few
聽，你聽
Listen, listen
她在向你呼喚
She's calling to you
喂餵這些小鳥
Feed the birds
一袋兩便士
Tuppence a bag
只要兩便士
Tuppence, tuppence
兩便士一袋
Tuppence a bag
雖然老婦人的叫賣聲
Though her words
微弱而簡單
Are simple and few
聽，你聽
Listen, listen
她在向你呼喚
She's calling to you
喂餵這些小鳥
Feed the birds
一袋兩便士
Tuppence a bag
只要兩便士
Tuppence, tuppence
兩便士
Tuppence
一袋
A bag
現在給我記住，銀行是一個安靜且莊重的地方。所以要表現出我們最好的舉止
Now remember that a bank is a quiet and decorous place, so we must be on our best behaviour.
我還以為那是你的銀行 好吧，我是銀行裏面一個年輕的職員……
But I thought it was your bank.
Yes, well, I'm one of the younger officers...
所以在某種程度上是，有那麼幾分
so in a sense it is, sort of.
邁克爾，看！
Michael, look!
是她 誰？
It's her!
Who?
她是誰？ 賣鳥食的老婦人，就像瑪麗?潑平斯所描述的
It's who?
The bird woman. Just where Mary Poppins said she would be.
你確實看到她了，對吧，父親？ 當然我能看到她
You do see her, don't you, Father?
Well, of course I can see her.
離我眼皮子這麼近的我能看不到？
Do you think I can't see past the end of my nose?
聽，父親，她在叫賣
Listen, Father, she's saying it.
喂喂小鳥，一袋兩便士
Feed the birds. Tuppence a bag.
當然她在叫賣，她還能說別的什麼嗎？
Well, of course she's saying it. What else would she be saying?
我們能喂餵這些小鳥嗎？ 為什麼？
Please may we feed the birds?
Whatever for?
我從我的儲蓄罐裏面拿了兩便士 就這一次，求求你了
I have tuppence from my money box.
Just this once, please?
把你的錢浪費在一群骯髒的鳥身上？當然不行
Waste your money on a lot of ragamuffin birds? Certainly not.
但是瑪麗?潑平斯說…… 我對瑪麗?潑平斯說得話不感興趣
But Mary Poppins...
I am not interested in what Mary Poppins says.
今天也不想再聽到她的名字。現在快跟上來！
Nor do I wish to keep hearing her name for the remainder of the day. Now come along!
但這是我的兩便士！
But it's my tuppence!
邁克爾，我決不允許你把錢這樣扔掉！
Michael, I will not permit you to throw your money away!
等我們到了銀行，我會教你該怎麼處置你的兩便士
When we get to the bank, I shall show you what may be done with your tuppence.
我想你也會發現這會非常有意思
And I think you'll find it extremely interesting.
你好，班克斯。這些都是誰？
Hello, Banks. What's all this about?
道斯先生，它們都是我的孩子 我想也是
These are my children, Mr Dawes.
Well, so I assumed.
但他們在這裏幹什麼？ 他們想開一個戶頭
But why are they here?
They wish to open an account, sir.
真的？ 是的
Oh, indeed?
Yes.
那麼年輕人，你有多少錢呢？
And just how much money do you have, young man?
兩便士。但是我想用來買鳥食 噓！
Tuppence. But I want it to feed the birds.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
兩便士
Tuppence?
兩便士？恰好就是我起家的資金
Tuppence? Precisely how I started.
那是銀行的主席，老道斯先生
That's the chairman of the bank, the elder Mr Dawes.
金融界的一位偉人（也可翻譯為巨人，大力士）
A giant in the world of finance.
一個大力士？ 噓！
A giant?
Shh, shh, shh.
唔，父親，這些是班克斯的孩子
Uh, Father, these are Banks's children.
他們想來開個戶頭 噢，是麼，孩子？
They want to open an account.
Oh, they do, do they, boy?
好極了，好極了
Excellent. Excellent.
我們總，總能讓……
We can al-always use...
讓錢發揮更大的作用，對吧？孩子
al-always use more money to, to put to work for the bank, can't we, boy?
這麼說，你有兩便士？
So, you have tuppence?
我能看看嗎？
May I be permitted to see it?
不，我想用它來買鳥食，喂鳥
No. I want it to feed the birds!
胡說！喂鳥，你能得到什麼？更胖的鳥？
Fiddlesticks, boy! Feed the birds and what have you got? Fat birds!
但是，如果你把你的兩便士
But if you invest your tuppence
明智地存入銀行
Wisely in the bank
兩便士將完好無損
Safe and sound
很快，那安全地投資在銀行裏的兩便士
Soon that tuppence safely invested in the bank
會滋生利息
Will compound
當財富不斷地膨脹
And you'll achieve that sense of conquest
你將獲得成就感
As your affluence expands
（你的錢）在一群
In the hands
懂得
Of the directors
恰當投資的
Who invest
銀行經理手中
As propriety demands
我來解釋吧，先生？ 來吧，班克斯
May I, sir?
Carry on, Banks.
你瞧，邁克爾，你將會成為如下項目的投資人……
You see, Michael, you'll be part of...
穿越非洲大陸的鐵路 完全正確
Railways through Africa
Exactly!
尼羅河大壩 還有那船，告訴他們船的投資
Dams across the Nile
The ships. Tell them about the ships.
遠洋快輪 還有，都告訴他們
Fleets of ocean greyhounds
More, tell them more!
偉大的自我分期還貸的運河
Majestic self-amortizing canals
哦，想像力真豐富！
Oh, it fires the imagination!
成熟的大莊園
Plantations of ripening
茶葉
Tea
所有的這一切都來自於
All from
將兩便士明智地，成功地，節儉地
Tuppence prudently thriftily, frugally
投資在 這很明確
Invested in the
To be specific
道斯 托姆斯 莫斯利 格魯布斯
In the Dawes, Tomes Mousley, Grubbs
信託投資銀行
Fidelity Fiduciary Bank
很好，孩子，把錢給我 不，我不要，我要拿去買鳥食喂鳥
Very well, my boy, give me the money.
No, I won't! I want it to feed the birds.
班克斯！ 是的，先生，馬上給他，邁克爾
Banks!
Yes, sir. Now, Michael.
當你在銀行的戶頭上存入兩便士
When you deposit tuppence in a bank account
繼續 很快你將看見
Go on!
Soon you'll see
都告訴他！ 半年後，它將
Tell him more!
That it blooms into credit of a generous amount
發展成為一筆巨大的財富
Semiannually
當財富不斷地膨脹
And you'll achieve that sense of stature
你將獲得成就感
As your influence expands
建立信貸機構的
To the high financial strata
金融界最高層人士現在宣佈
That established credit now commands
你可以購買第一和第二類信託契約
You can purchase first and second trust deeds.
想像一下回贖抵押品權利的取消所發生的事情吧！
Think of the foreclosures!
債券，個人資產，股息，股票
Bonds, chattels, dividends, shares.
破產 債權轉讓
Bankruptcies.
Debtor sales.
機遇 各種形形色色的私人企業
Opportunities.
All manner of private enterprise.
船塢 商船
Shipyards.
The mercantile.
煤礦 皮革廠
Collieries.
Tanneries.
公司 合併 銀行
Corporations.
Amalgamations.
Banks!
當英格蘭的銀行興旺時……
While stand the banks of England...
英格蘭屹立不倒
England stands.
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
但英格蘭的銀行倒閉時……
When fall the banks of England...
英格蘭沒落
England falls!
你看到麼嗎，邁克爾？所有這一切都因
You see, Michael? All for the lack of...
缺乏對兩便士進行耐心地，謹慎地
Tuppence patiently, cautiously
信賴地投資在
trustingly invested in the
這很明確
To be specific In the
道斯 托姆斯 莫斯利 格魯布斯
Dawes, Tomes, Mousley, Grubbs
信託投資銀行
Fidelity Fiduciary Bank
歡迎來到我們這個快樂的投資者大家庭
Welcome to our joyful family of investors.
還給我！把錢還給我！
Give it back! Gimme back my money!
邁克爾，注意你的舉止 班克斯！ 把錢還給我！
Michael, behave.
Banks!
Give it to me!
邁克爾，聽話！簡！簡！ 把錢還給我！
Michael, behave. Jane! Jane!
Gimme back my money!
簡！邁克爾！邁克爾！邁克爾！
Jane! Michael! Michael! Michael!
把錢還給我！ 邁克爾！
Gimme back my money!
Michael!
出了什麼問題。銀行拒絕兌現了
There's something wrong. The bank won't give someone their money!
天，我要拿回我的錢！你，年輕人，我要取回每一分錢！
Well, I'm going to get mine! Come along, young man! I want every penny!
我也要！ 還有我的！
And mine too!
And give me mine too!
停止兌付！
Stop all payments.
邁克爾！簡！ 把錢還給我！
Michael! Jane!
Give me my money!
孩子們，回來，攔住那些孩子，簡！邁克爾！
Children, come back here. Stop those children. Jane! Michael!
還給我錢！還我錢！
Gimme my money back! I want my money!
來吧
Come on.
攔住那些孩子！
Stop those children!
攔住孩子！
跟我來，親愛的。我幫你藏起來
Come with me, my dears. Granny'll hide you!
這兒，這兒，等一下 放開她，把我的姐姐放開！
Here, here, half a mo.
Leave her alone! Leave my sister alone!
嘿，沒事的，你們的老朋友不會傷害你的
Easy, now. Your old friend ain't gonna hurt ya.
伯特，是你啊！
Bert, it's you!
正是在下，聽從你的吩咐
In the flesh, and at your service.
你可真髒！ 哦，也許是有一兩處污漬
You're filthy!
Oh, perhaps a smudge or two.
碰巧今天我是個掃煙囪的人
It so happens that today I'm a chimney sweep.
哦，伯特，我們嚇得要命
Oh, Bert, we're so frightened.
好了，好了，現在不用害怕
Now, now, don't take on so.
伯特會向你們的父親那樣照顧好你們的
Bert'll take care of you like I was your own father.
誰在追你們？ 我們的父親……
Now, who's after you?
Father is.
什麼？ 他帶我們去他的銀行參觀
What?
He brought us to see his bank.
我不知道我們做了什麼，但一定是非常糟糕的事情
I don't know what we did, but it must've been something dreadful.
他讓警察追我們，還有軍隊，所有人都在追我們
He sent the police after us, and the Army and everything.
邁克爾，別這麼誇張
Michael, don't exaggerate.
好吧，一定有什麼誤會
Well, now, there must be some mistake.
你們的爸爸是個好人，他愛你們
Your dad's a fine gentleman and he loves ya!
不可不這樣認為。你最好能看見他當時的那張臉
I don't think so. You should've seen the look on his face.
他壓根就不喜歡我們
He doesn't like us at all.
好了，別好像好像的，好嗎？
Well, now that don't seem likely, does it?
這是事實
It's true.
讓我們坐一坐
Let's sit down.
你知道，……
You know, begging your pardon...
我很同情你們的父親
but the one my heart goes out to is your father.
他在那個冷酷的，無情的銀行中日復一日地……
There he is in that cold, heartless bank day after day...
被一大堆冰冷的，無感情的金錢所包圍
hemmed in by mounds of cold, heartless money.
我不喜歡看到任何生命被關在籠中
I don't like to see any living thing caged up.
父親被關在籠子裏了？
Father in a cage?
籠子的尺寸和形狀不同而已，你知道
They makes cages in all sizes and shapes, you know.
一些是銀行形狀的，用地毯什麼的來製作
Bank-shaped some of 'em, carpets and all.
父親沒有麻煩，我們有！
Father's not in trouble. We are.
哦，你們確信？
Oh, sure about that, are you?
換個角度想想，你們有你們的母親照顧你們
Look at it this way. You've got your mother to look after you.
還有瑪麗?潑平斯，瓊斯警察，還有我
And Mary Poppins, and Constable Jones and me.
誰來照顧你們的父親呢？你們說說看
Who looks after your father? Tell me that.
當一些可怕的事情發生時，他該怎麼辦？
When something terrible happens, what does he do?
他只能自己照顧自己
Fends for himself, he does.
他向誰傾訴？沒人！
Who does he tell about it? No one!
不能在家裏傾訴他的煩心事
Don't blab his troubles at home.
他只是毫無怨言，獨自一人，安靜地努力承受著
He just pushes on at his job, uncomplaining and alone and silent.
他並不是很安靜！ 邁克爾，安靜點
He's not very silent!
Michael, be quiet.
伯特，你確定父親真的需要我們的幫助嗎？
Bert, do you think Father really needs our help?
呃，這個我不該說的
Well, not my place to say.
我只注意到，一個父親常常需要那麼一點幫助
I only observe that a father can always do with a bit of help.
來吧，我帶你們回家
Come on, I'll take you home.
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
一個掃煙囪人就是幸運星
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
當我和你握手，好運就會傳染給你
Good luck will rub off when I shakes hands with you
或者和我接吻
Or blow me a kiss
好運也會傳染給你
And that's lucky too
當生活就想一串梯子
Now as the ladder of life has been strung
你可以想想在梯子最底端的掃煙囪人
You might think a sweep's on the bottommost rung
雖然我成天跟爐灰打交道
Though I spends me time in the ashes and smoke
但在這整個廣袤的世界裏，沒有其它傢伙能比我更快樂
In this whole wide world there's no happier bloke
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
一個掃煙囪人就是幸運星
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
當我和你握手，好運就會傳染給你
Good luck will rub off when I shakes hands with you
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
一個掃煙囪人就是幸運星
A sweep is as lucky as lucky can be
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheroo
當我和你握手，好運就會傳染給你
Good luck will rub off when I shakes hands with you
噢，艾倫，去看看是誰，把他們打發走
Oh, Ellen, see who that is, and send them away.
我已經遲到了！ 是的，夫人
I'm dreadfully late!
Yes, ma'am.
好了，我現在可以離開了。 哦別，請陪我們到父親回家來為止吧。
Well, I'll be gettin' along now.
Oh, please stay till Father comes home.
如果你跟他握手，他會感覺好多的。
He'll feel much better if you shake hands with him.
是孩子們 我想他們應該跟他們的父親在一起
It's the children, ma'am.
Oh, I thought they were with their father.
你們不是又逃跑了吧？你們知道這會讓我多痛苦嗎？
You haven't been running off again, have you? You know how terribly it upsets me.
哦夫人，準確地講他們並不是逃跑
Oh, they haven't exactly been running away, ma'am.
然而，他們受了點驚嚇，需要有人照顧
They have had bit of a fright, though. Need someone to look after 'em.
哦，當然！瑪麗?潑平斯會照顧他們的
Oh, of course! Mary Poppins will.
噢，不，今天她休假
Oh, no, it's her day off!
艾倫，我想請你…… 不行，夫人，我自己的活還沒有幹完呢
Ellen, I wonder if you would...
No, ma'am. I haven't done me brasses yet.
好吧，你能問一下布裏夫人嗎？ 就算給我一百英鎊，我也不幹，夫人
Well, will you ask Mrs Brill?
Not for a hundred quid, ma'am.
今天是烘焙日，你知道要煮多少東西麼！
This here is baking day, and you know how Cook is!
你怎麼樣，先生？
What about you, sir?
你剛才已經非常熱心地照顧這些孩子了
You've been so kind in looking after the children.
唔……我嗎？夫人，我……我不得不離開
Wh... Uh, me, ma'am? W-Well, well, l-l-I have to be moving along.
市長大人家的煙囪被堵住了
The Lord Mayor's got a stopped-up chimney.
煙囪，你可真聰明
Chimney. How clever of you to know.
我們客廳的煙囪糟糕透了。煙不斷地往客廳冒
Our drawing room chimney's in the most ghastly condition. Smokes incessantly.
唔…… 非常謝謝！
W-W...
Thank you so much!
但，但是…… 還有，順便帶好孩子
But...
Besides, it'll amuse the children.
市長大人家的馬上就要劇烈地噴發了
The Lord Mayor's gonna be terrible put out.
哦，謝謝你，我會非常感激的
Oh, thank you so much. I do appreciate it.
我必須得走了。我們勇敢的姐妹在監獄中正等著我領她們唱歌呢！
I must hurry. Our gallant ladies in prison are waiting for me to lead them in song!
再見，親愛的，一會兒見
Goodbye, my darlings. See you soon.
我驕傲地挑選豬鬃工具，是的，我驕傲
I choose me bristles with pride, yes, I do
掃帚用來掃煙囪，用刷子來通煙道
A broom for the shaft and a brush for the flue
這裏很黑很暗
Oh, it's awfully dark and gloomy up there.
現在，你將知道你的看法是錯誤的
There now. You see how wrong people can be?
這兒是通向你所謂魔法世界的一條通道
That there is what you might call a doorway to a place of enchantment.
在上面煙霧如巨浪般翻滾，捲曲
Up where the smoke is all billowed and curled
在星星和地面之間
'Tween pavement and stars
是掃煙囪人的世界
Is the chimney sweep world
這裏幾乎沒有白天
When there's hardly no day
也幾乎沒有黑夜
Nor hardly no night
所有的事物一半在陰影裏
There's things half in shadow
一半在光線下
And halfway in light
站在倫敦的屋頂
On the rooftops of London
視野真開闊
Coo, what a sight.
我真希望我們能到上面去
I do wish we could go up there.
我也是！我喜歡煙囪
So do I! I like chimneys.
非常正確！煙囪是一件完美的東西
Oh, rightly so! A chimney is a wondrous thing.
她高高地建在屋頂上
She's built tall right up there on the roof.
當風向正確的時候，風吹過她的頂端
When the wind is just right, it blows across her top...
驅動煙從煙道中穿過
then draws the smoke right up the flue.
拿著，用刷子感受一下底部的吸力
Here. Feel the pull on the end of that brush.
這就好像站在鯨魚噴水口的底部
It's like I got a whale on the end of the line, ain't it?
邁克爾，小心，你永遠不知道站在壁爐旁邊會發生什麼事情
Michael, be careful. You never know what may happen around a fireplace.
天啦！
Oh, bother!
邁克爾，邁克爾，下來！
Michael! Michael, come back down here.
邁克爾，你在哪裏？
Michael! Michael, where are you?
好吧，我不得不說，這有點尷尬！
Well, that's a bit awkward. I must say!
伯特，麻煩你不要出餿主意了！
Bert, I'll thank you to stop putting ideas in their heads!
現在輪到下一個 我能跟在後面麼？
There goes the other one.
Shall I go after 'em?
我們不能讓他們像袋鼠一樣在上面閒逛，對吧？
Well, we can't have them gallivanting up there like kangaroos, can we?
邁克爾，別害怕。事情正在……
Michael, don't be frightened. Everything's going...
你能立刻把你的東西放下嗎？
Will you put your things on at once?
請快一點
Hurry up, please. Spit spot!
你在這兒！我以為你丟下我們了。 我們沒有這個意思
Here you are! I thought you'd left us.
We didn't mean to.
真好，一切平安無事。事實上……
Well, no harm done. The truth is...
這是你們所說的偶發事件
this is what you might call a fortuitous circumstance.
看那兒
Look there.
一個茂密的雨林正等著我們去探索
A trackless jungle just waiting to be explored.
為什麼不行，瑪麗?潑平斯？ 求求你了，瑪麗?潑平斯
Why not, Mary Poppins?
Oh, please, Mary Poppins?
Please!
好吧，如果這是必要的
Oh, well. If we must, we must.
同意
Fall in.
精神點，精神點。跟上！跟上！
Look lively, look lively. Jump to it! Jump to it!
排成一列，立正！
Get in line. Attention!
扛槍！
A-show arms!
向右轉！
A-right turn!
齊步走！
Quick march!
喂，那兒！
Hello there!
很好，擦乾淨，邁克爾
It's just good, clean soot, Michael.
我們只能走到這裏了，是嗎？ 當然不
As far as we go, right?
Not at all.
我說什麼來著？整個世界都在你腳下
What did I tell ya? There's the whole world at your feet.
只有鳥兒、星星和掃煙囪人見過
And who gets to see it, but the birds, the stars and the chimney sweeps?
真棒，但我們必須走出這片夜色
Quite nice, but we should all get in out of the night air.
請跟我來
Follow me, please.
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy, chim chiminy
Chim chim cheree
當你和一個掃煙囪人在一起，就如同與歡樂在一起
When you're with a sweep you're in glad company
哪兒都不如一群快樂的人群
Nowhere is there a more happier crew
他們都這樣唱著
Then them what sings chim chim cheree, chim cheroo
黑煙囪……冒黑煙……
Chim chiminy chim chim
冒黑煙……
Cheree chim cheroo
- Cheroo!
這些都是我的哥們！
It's all me pals!
來跳舞！
Step in time!
來吧，朋友，來跳舞
Step in time, step in time Come on, mateys, step in time
來跳舞
Step in time
Step in time, step in time
step in time, step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由，我們來跳舞，來跳舞
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
We step in time, we step in time
提起你的膝蓋！
Kick your knees up! Kick your knees up, Step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Kick your knees up, step in time
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
提起你的膝蓋
Kick your knees up step in time
圍著煙囪！
Round the chimney!
Round the chimney, Step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Round the chimney, step in time
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
圍著煙囪！我們跳舞
Round the chimney We step in time
像鳥兒一樣拍打
Clap like a birdie.
Clap like a birdie, Step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Clap like a birdie, step in time
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
像鳥兒一樣拍打
Clap like a birdie
In time
爬上欄杆
Up on the railing.
Up on the railing, Step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Up on the railing, step in time
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
爬上欄杆
Up on the railing
Step in time
跨過屋頂
Over the rooftops!
Over the rooftops, Step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Over the rooftops, step in time
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
跨過屋頂
Step it time, over the rooftops
over the rooftops
站成一排踢腿！
Link your elbows!
站成一排踢腿
Link your elbows, step in time
Link your elbows
link your elbows, link your elbows
來跳舞
Step in time, step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
When you step in time, You step in time
瑪麗?潑平斯，來跳舞！
Mary Poppins, step in time!
來吧，瑪麗?潑平斯！
There you go, Mary Poppins!
哦，伯特！
Lucky old Bert!
來吧
Come on, Mary Poppins!
來，夥計！
Here we go, mate!
來
Here we go!
給她讓點地方！
Make room for her! Go!
她真不可思議！她真漂亮！
Ain't she marvellous? Ain't she beautiful?
真可愛
Lovely. Tell your mum!
好啊
Hello, hello, hello!
再來！瑪麗?潑平斯，再來一遍！
More! More! Mary, do it again!
Come on, Mary, do it again.
我們來
Here we go.
我們正被霍屯督人攻擊！ 是的，將軍。
We're being attacked by Hottentots!
Aye, aye, sir.
這幫魔鬼！ 給他們點教訓！
Cheeky devils! Give 'em what for!
清空炮膛 遵命，將軍！
Empty the shot lockers!
Aye, aye, sir!
動起來，班納克先生。慢一點，給這些乞丐一點教訓。
Move along, Mr Binnacle. Handsomely now. Teach the beggars a lesson.
大炮準備好了，將軍。 預備
Gun ready, sir.
Stand by.
開火！
Fire!
正中目標！ 很好！
Well hit, sir!
Very well hit!
嘿！他們又來了！
Aah! They're at it again!
他們又來了！
They're at it again, Step it time
At it again, Step in time
他們又來了
They're at it again
Step in time
Ow!
Ow, step in time
從不需要原因，從不需要理由
Never need a reason, Never need a rhyme
Whoa!
Step in time
哦，艾倫，你什麼時候有空。
Oh, Ellen, when you have a second.
爭取婦女的投票權！
Votes for women, step in time
不，真的，這時候不行。
Oh, no, really, not at the moment.
爭取婦女投票權！
Votes for women!
主人回來了！
It's the master!
It's the master, step in time It's the master, step in time
這都是些什麼？
What's all this?
What's all this
這都是些什麼
What's all this, What's all this
排成一列踢腿。來跳舞
Link your elbows, step in time
What's all this?
提起你的膝蓋
Kick your knees up
What's all this? Step in time
伯特。
Kick your knees up, Kick your knees up
Bert.
Kick your knees up
提起你的膝蓋
Kick your knees up in time
祝好運，老爸，多美好的時光
Good luck, guv'nor.
Lovely time!
祝你有個文雅的時光，老爸
Had an elegant time, guv'nor.
祝好運，老爸
Good luck, guv'nor.
哦，父親，這些掃煙囪人都握過你的手
Oh, Father, every one of those sweeps shook your hand.
你將會變成世界上最幸運的人！
You're going to be the luckiest person in the world!
來吧，孩子們，快點 等一等，瑪麗?潑平斯
Come along, children. Spit spot.
Just a moment, Mary Poppins.
這簡直是件駭人聽聞的事件
What is the meaning of this outrage?
你再說一遍？ 你最好給我一個合理的解釋
I beg your pardon?
Will you be good enough to explain all this?
首先，我願明確地解釋一件事情
First of all, I would like to make one thing quite clear.
什麼？
Yes?
我從不解釋任何事
I never explain anything.
是，我是班克斯
Yes. Banks here.
道斯先生！我非常非常的抱歉。關於今天在銀行發生的事情
Mr Dawes! I'm most dreadfully sorry, sir, about what happened at the bank today.
我可以保證…… 今晚，先生？
I can assure you that...
Tonight, sir?
是的，班克斯。我們希望你9點準時到達
Yes, Banks. We'll expect you at 9:00 precisely.
不能遲到
Without fail.
為什麼，班克斯。
Why, yes, Banks.
這是極其嚴重的事件
It's extremely serious.
我們對這一系列決定非常遺憾
We regret this course of action.
我們非常遺憾
畢竟，你和我們共事多年
After all, you have been with us a good many years.
畢竟，共事多年 在此之前是你的父親
As was your father before you.
之前是你的父親
是的，道斯先生。我會9點到
Yes, Mr Dawes. I shall be there at 9:00.
一個男人夢想著與巨人同行
A man has dreams of walking with giants.
在漫漫人生旅途中雕琢環境
To carve his niche in the edifice of time.
在他的熱情
Before the mortar of his zeal
凝固之前
Has a chance to congeal
獎盃是獎勵給衝過終點線的人！
The cup is dashed from his lips!
激情尚未迸發便被澆滅
The flame is snuffed a-borning.
他在他全盛時期被毀滅
He's brought to wrack and ruin in his prime.
生活就像一杯朗姆酒，老爸。這是事實。
Life is a rum go, guv'nor. And that's the truth.
你知道我想什麼嗎？是那個女人——瑪麗?潑平斯說的。
You know what I think?
It's that woman Mary Poppins.
從她踏進這所房子的那一刻開始，許多事情就發生了！
From the moment she stepped into this house, things began to happen to me!
瑪麗?潑平斯？ 是的，當然。
Mary Poppins?
Yes, yes, of course.
我的世界曾經平靜
My world was calm
井然有序，值得效仿
Well-ordered Exemplary.
自打這個人帶著被她喚醒的
Then came this person
混亂，來了以後
With chaos in her wake
現在我生活的抱負一下子
And now my life's ambitions go
被打倒了
With one fell blow
這是相當難以
It's quite a bitter pill
表述的
To take.
這就那個姓潑平斯的女人！就是她造成的！
It's that Poppins woman! She did it!
我知道你說的這個女人
I know the very person you mean.
瑪麗?潑平斯，她就是那個唱著……
Mary Poppins. She's the one what sings...
一湯匙糖
A spoonful of sugar
那就是全部
That is all it takes
它把麵包和水
It changes bread and water
變成了茶和蛋糕
Into tea and cakes
你明白了嗎？那正是我的意思！
You see? That's exactly what I mean!
把麵包和水變成茶和蛋糕！確實是！
Changing bread and water into tea and cakes! Indeed!
難怪這裏每件事情都雜亂無章
No wonder everything's higgledy-piggledy here.
一湯匙糖
A spoonful of sugar
每天走很長很長的路
Goes a long, long way
有助於你的
Have yourself a healthy helpin'
健康
Every day
如果你問我，一個有益健康的問題
An healthy helpin' of trouble, if you ask me.
你知道她怎麼做的嗎？我現在意識到了
Do you know what she did? I realize it now.
她慫恿我帶簡和邁克爾來銀行
She tricked me into taking Jane and Michael to the bank.
這正是所有麻煩的開始
That's how all the trouble started.
慫恿你帶孩子們出門遠足？ 是的
Tricked you into taking the children on an outing?
Yes.
真無恥！
Outrageous!
一個男人有許多重要的事情要去做。真可恥！
A man with all the important things you have to do. Shameful!
你是一個有身份的男人
You're a man of high position.
受同齡人的尊敬
Esteemed by your peers.
當你的孩子們哭泣的時候
And when your little tykes are cryin'
你沒有時間去擦乾他們的眼淚
You haven't time to dry their tears
瞧瞧他們感激地小臉蛋
And see them grateful little faces
衝著你微笑
Smilin' up at you
因為他們的爸爸
Because their dad
總是知道什麼是應該做的
He always knows just what to do
呃，我的意思是，瞧，我不認為我…… 就像你說的，老爸
Well, I mean, look, I, I don't think I ca...
Like you say, guv'nor.
你不得不在石磨上
You've got to grind, grind, grind
不停地磨呀磨呀磨
At that grindstone
雖然童年時光
Though childhood slips
就像沙子穿過沙漏
Like sand through a sieve
很快他們就長大
And all too soon they've up and grown
接著他們就離你而去
And then they've flown
那時你再後悔
And it's too late
就太遲了
For you to give
就好像一湯匙糖
Just that spoonful of sugar
能夠幫助把藥服下
To help the medicine go down
甜藥
The medicine go down
好入口
Medicine go down
好了，再見，老爸，很抱歉給你惹了這麼多麻煩
Well, goodbye, guv'nor. Sorry to have troubled you.
父親？
Father?
我們對兩便士的事情非常抱歉
We're sorry about the tuppence.
我們不知道那會引起這麼大的麻煩
We didn't know it would cause you so much trouble.
父親，給你兩便士
Here, Father, you can have the tuppence.
這樣能平息所有的風波嗎？
Will that make everything all right?
謝謝
Thank you.
進來!
Come in!
把帽子脫掉，班克斯
Take your hat off, Banks.
晚上好，先生們
Good evening, gentlemen.
很好，繼續
Well, get on with it. Go on.
是，父親
Uh, yes, Father.
在1773年，這家銀行的一位職員……
In 1773, an official of this bank...
愚蠢地將一大筆錢借給
unwisely loaned a large sum of money...
往北美殖民地海運茶葉的貿易
to finance a shipment of tea to the American colonies.
知道後來發生了什麼事？ 是的，先生，我想我知道
Do you know what happened?
Yes, sir. Yes, I think I do.
當船停泊在波士頓港的時候
Uh, uh, as the ship lay in Boston Harbor...
一群殖民地居民打扮成印第安人
uh, a party of the colonists dressed as red Indians...
登上了船，舉止非常粗魯，還將所有的茶葉傾倒到海裏
uh, boarded the vessel, behaved very rudely, and, and threw all the tea overboard.
導致茶葉味道變質
This made the tea unsuitable for drinking...
即使是美國人也不願意喝
even for Americans.
很對。這筆借款成了呆賬
Precisely. The loan was defaulted.
在這堵牆內的恐慌接踵而至
Panic ensued within these walls.
銀行發生了擠兌事件！
There was a run on the bank!
從那時起到現在，先生……
From that time to this, sir...
這家銀行還沒有發生過一起擠兌事件
there has not been a run on this bank...
直到今天！
until today!
一場擠兌事件，先生，起因是你兒子的可恥的行為
A run, sir, caused by the disgraceful conduct of your son.
對此你否認嗎？ 我不否認，先生
Do you deny it?
I do not deny it, sir.
我只能情願為我兒子的行為承擔責任
And I shall be only too glad to assume responsibility for my son.
你還在等什麼？繼續！ 是，是的，父親
What are you waiting for? Get on with it!
Uh, y-yes, Father.
不，別這樣！ 鎮定！
No, not that!
Steady on.
好了，班克斯，你還有什麼話要說的嗎？
Well, do you have anything to say, Banks?
先生，他們說……
Well, sir, they do say that...
當你無話可說的時候，你就可以說……
when there's nothing to say, all you can say i...
班克斯，請搞清楚！我問，你還有什麼說的嗎？
Confound it, Banks! I said, do you have anything to say?
只有一個詞，先生 什麼詞？
Just one word, sir.
Yes?
超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious.
什麼？
What?
超級霹靂快樂得不得了
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious.
瑪麗?潑平斯是對的。這個詞很特別，確實能讓你感覺好多了！
Mary Poppins was right. It's extraordinary. It does make you feel better!
你在說什麼？沒有這個詞
What are you talking about, man? There's no such word.
不，有這個詞。實際上，它是一個完美的詞
Oh, yes. It is a word. A perfectly good word, actually.
你知道有這樣的事情嗎？
Do you know what there's no such thing as?
當所有的事情都說過並做過後，發生……
It turns out, with due respect, when all is said and done...
像你這樣的事情……
that there's no such thing as you!
主題，先生！注意談話的主題
Impertinence, sir! Speaking of impertinence...
你想聽一個絕妙的笑話嗎？
would you like to hear a perfectly marvellous joke?
一個真正的笑話！ 笑話？真正的？
A real snapper!
Joke? Snapper?
是的，有兩個優秀的年輕人，簡和邁克爾
Yes. There are these two wonderful young people, Jane and Michael.
有一天他們在街上相遇，簡跟邁克爾說
And they meet one day on the street, and Jane says to Michael...
我知道一個有一隻木頭假腿的人，名字叫史密斯 （也可理解為：我知道有個人，他有一隻叫做史密斯的木頭假腿）
"I know a man with a wooden leg named Smith."
邁克爾問，真的？那他的另一隻腿叫什麼？
And Michael says, "Really? What's the name of his other leg?"
這個人瘋了，叫警衛
The man's gone mad. Call the guard!
超級霹靂快樂得不得了，我感覺好極了！
Supercalifragilistic-expialidocious. I'm feeling better all the time!
班克斯，不准你打擊我的父親！
Banks, don't you dare strike my father!
這是那兩便士 這是命中注定的，絕妙的
There's the tuppence. The wonderful, fateful...
超級霹靂快樂得不得了 的兩便士
supercalifragilistic-expialidocious tuppence.
好好保護它，再見！ 班克斯，你要去哪兒？
Guard it well. Goodbye!
Banks, where are you going?
我不知道 也許跳進馬路上的粉筆畫裏
I don't know. I might pop through a chalk pavement picture,
去鄉下遠足
and go for an outing in the country.
或者騎著一匹旋轉木馬，贏得賽馬比賽
Or I might seize a horse off a merry-go-round, and win the Derby!
或者僅僅去放風箏！這只有潑平斯知道！
Or I might just fly a kite! Only Poppins would know!
潑平斯？ 我的保姆。那首荒謬的歌就是她唱的。
Poppins?
My nanny. She's the one who sings that ridiculous song.
一湯匙糖讓苦藥服下
A spoonful of sugar makes the medicine go down
甜藥好入口
The medicine go down
甜藥好入口……
The medicine go down The medicine...
像三月裏的野兔般瘋狂
Mad as a March hare.
一隻叫史密斯的木假腿
A wooden leg named Smith.
史密斯有條木假腿
木假腿……
A wooden le...
父親？父親！
Father? Father!
父親，下來！
Father, come down!
爸爸，爸爸！回來！
Daddy! Daddy, come back!
風向轉變了，非常精確地從西邊刮來！
Wind's come around, blowing dead on from the west!
她不關心我們身上發生的事情
She doesn't care what happens to us.
她只答應呆到風向轉變為止。是吧，瑪麗?潑平斯？
She only promised to stay till the wind changed. Isn't that right, Mary Poppins?
請把衣帽架遞過來好嗎？
Will you bring me my hat stand, please?
瑪麗?潑平斯，你不愛我們了嗎？
Mary Poppins, don't you love us?
不關心我們的遭遇了嗎？
And what would happen to me
may I ask...
請問如果我愛所有的小孩，我該給誰告別呢？
if I loved all the children I said goodbye to?
是的，先生，沒錯。喬治 W 班克斯
Yes, sir, that's right. George W. Banks.
櫻桃樹大街17號
17 Cherry Tree Lane.
大約6英尺高，是的。
About six foot one, I'd say, sir.
是的，今天早上第一件事情就是給他工作的銀行打了電話
Oh, yes, we rang up his bank first thing this morning.
目前我們所知道的唯一事情就是，他昨晚就已經離開了
The only thing we discovered was, he'd been discharged last night.
他很沮喪，沒說要幹什麼
No telling what he might do in a fit of despondency.
不會去投河吧？
Wouldn't hurt to have them drag the river.
在薩克福橋附近有一個非常合適的地點，因投河自盡而聞名
There's a nice spot there by Suffolk Bridge. Popular with jumpers.
真的，艾倫！
Really, Ellen!
他看上去還不錯，很鎮定，先生
He seemed to have been a fine, stable gentleman, sir.
沒有陰謀，如果你知道我的意思。
No hanky-panky, if you know what I mean.
呃，日常習慣嘛。幾乎沒有人知道 甜藥好入口
Oh, regular habits, sir. Well, far as anyone knows.
The medicine go down
甜藥好入口
只要一湯匙糖 是他！
Just a spoonful of sugar
It's him!
幫你把苦藥…… 或者聲音聽起來像是他
Helps the medicine
Or something that sounds like him.
服下 班克斯夫人，能不能讓房子裏的人小聲一點
Go down
Mrs Banks, could we have a little less noise...
我聽不到警長的聲音了 他現在很興奮
on the premises? I can't make out what the inspector's sayin'.
In the most delightful way
只要一湯匙糖
Just a spoonful of sugar
讓苦藥服下 喬治！
Makes the medicine go down
George!
哦，喬治，你沒有去投河
Oh, George, you didn't jump in the river.
你真明智啊
How sensible of you.
好了，先生，找到他了！
It's all right, sir. He's been found!
不，還活著！
No, alive!
或者我以為。他正在親吻班克斯夫人
Or so I presume. He's a-kissin' a-Mrs. Banks.
我真的很擔心，在銀行發生了什麼事情？
I've been so worried. What happened at the bank?
我被解雇了，趕了出來，扔到了大街上
I've been sacked, discharged, flung into the street.
一湯匙糖能讓苦藥服下
A spoonful of sugar makes the medicine go down
他剛才的行為有點不正常
Gone off his crumpet. That's what he's done.
甜藥好入口 瘋瘋癲癲的
The medicine go down
Dotty as you please.
喬治，你在地下室到底在做什麼？
George, what on earth were you doing in the cellar?
一會兒你就知道了。孩子們在哪裏？簡？邁克爾？
You'll see in a moment. Where are the children? Jane? Michael?
你們的父親在叫。 聽起來不像是父親的聲音
Your father's calling you.
It doesn't sound like Father.
簡？邁克爾？ 快跑去吧
Jane? Michael?
Run along. Spit spot!
你不會走吧，瑪麗?潑平斯？
You won't go, Mary Poppins, will you?
快！快！
Spit spot.
他修好了！
He mended it!
太好了！ 你怎麼修的？
It's wonderful!
However did you manage it?
花兩便士買了紙和繩子
With tuppence for paper and strings
雙腳站在地上
You can have your own set of wings
你可以讓風箏擁有自己的翅膀 緊緊抓住繩子
With your feet on the ground
You're a bird in flight
你就能像鳥兒一樣飛翔
With your fist holding tight
來放飛你的風箏吧
To the string of your kite
吼，吼，吼
Oh, oh, oh
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它飛向空中的最高處
Up to the highest height
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
穿越雲層
Up through the atmosphere
直達晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
哦，讓我們去放風箏
Oh, let's go fly a kite
你不認為，一個好風箏需要一條合適的尾巴嗎？
A proper kite needs a proper tail, don't you think?
那是我說的，先生。去放飛風箏！
That's what I said, sir. Go fly a kite!
哦，不，先生。我不是說你
Oh, no, sir. No, I, I don't mean you personally.
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它飛向空中的最高處
Up to the highest height
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
穿越雲層
Up through the atmosphere
直達晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
哦，讓我們去放風箏
Oh, let's go fly a kite
當你高高地放飛風箏
When you send it flying up there
立刻你會感覺自己比空氣還輕
All at once you're lighter than air
你能在吹過房子和樹林的風裏起舞
You can dance on the breeze over houses and trees
用你的手緊緊握住繩子
With your fist holding tight
繫上你的風箏
To the string of your kite
放！
Oh, oh, oh
Now!
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它飛向空中的最高處
Up to the highest height
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
班克斯，你在這裏啊
Oh, there you are, Banks.
我要祝賀你
I want to congratulate you.
絕妙的笑話。叫史密斯的木腿
Capital bit of humour. Wooden leg named Smith.
或者瓊斯或者其他
Or Jones or whatever it was.
父親在笑中死去
Father died laughing.
噢，我很抱歉，先生 不，沒什麼可抱歉的。
Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
- Oh, no, nonsense. Nothing to be sorry about.
在他的一生中從沒有見他這麼快活過
Never seen him happier in his life.
他留下了一個新合夥人職位的空檔
He left an opening for a new partner.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
謝謝你，先生 真的謝謝你
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much indeed, sir.
穿越雲層
Up through the atmosphere
直達晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
哦，讓我們一起
Oh, let's go
去放風箏
Fly a kite
這需要感謝你
That's gratitude for you.
甚至沒有說聲再見嗎？ 是，他們沒說
Didn't even say goodbye.
No, they didn't.
看看他們，你知道，你跟他們的父親相比，他們更想念父親
Look at them. You know, they think more of their father than they do of you.
那是自然 好吧，你不在乎？
That's as it should be.
Well, don't you care?
近乎完美的人從不允許在他們的思想中摻雜個人感情
Practically perfect people never permit sentiment to muddle their thinking.
真的是這樣？我告訴你，瑪麗?潑平斯，你別騙我了。
Is that so? Well, I'll tell you one thing, Mary Poppins, you don't fool me a bit.
真的？ 真的！我完全知道你對這些孩子們的感情
Oh, really?
Yes, really. I know exactly how you feel about these children.
如果你會認為我繼續保持沉默，我……
And if you think I'm gonna keep my mouth shut any longer, I...
那就乖乖地閉上嘴，謝謝
That will be quite enough of that, thank you.
再見，瑪麗?潑平斯。別離開太久
Goodbye, Mary Poppins. Don't stay away too long.
吼，吼，吼
Oh, oh, oh
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它飛向空中的最高處
Up to the highest height
讓我們去放風箏
Let's go fly a kite
讓它在空中翱翔
And send it soaring
穿越雲層
Up through the atmosphere
直達晴朗的天空
Up where the air is clear
哦，讓我們一起去
Oh, let's go
放風箏
Fly a kite